<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Bong Eats</title>
  <subtitle>Bong Eats is about food from Bengal. And that&#39;s not just Bengali food.</subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://bongeats.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-12-30T04:20:12.787Z</updated>
  <id>https://bongeats.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Bong Eats</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Begun Bhaja</title>
    <link href="https://bongeats.com/recipe/begun-bhaja/"/>
    <id>https://bongeats.com/recipe/begun-bhaja/</id>
    <published>2016-12-29T17:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-12-30T04:20:12.787Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p class="post-byline">The goodness of perfectly seasoned, pan-fried brinjals</p>

<p class="post-intro">This is a recipe of brinjal fried to an amber-coloured crust on the outside, while remaining soft and mushy inside.</p>

<a id="more"></a>
<p><span class="dropcap">T</span>he taste of <em>begun bhaja</em> is difficult to explain to anyone who hasn’t eaten fried brinjals. Suffice it to say that it is probably unlike anything you’ve ever tasted, especially if seasoned with the right amount of salt and sugar. And we won’t even go into how drop-dead gorgeous the finished product is. The recipe is ridiculously simple. You smear thickly sliced brinjals in turmeric and seasoning, and fry them on medium heat in a skillet. The sugar in the marinade allows the brinjals to develop a wonderfully amber-coloured crust, and deepens the flavour of the dish. If you have 20 minutes to spare, give this recipe a try. Eat it along with steaming rice and dal, and you will not regret it. </p>
<p>This recipe uses one large brinjal. When shopping for the vegetable, be sure to select a specimen of the male variety as it is likely to contain far fewer seeds than its female counterpart. You can identify the type of the brinjal by looking at the indentation on its bottom. If the indentation is elongated and deep, it’s a female brinjal. And if it is round and shallow, that’s the seedless, male brinjal.</p><p></p>
<hr>
<p><strong>COOKING TIME</strong> 20 minutes<br><strong>YIELDS</strong> 6 slices of <em>begun bhaja</em></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="Ingredients"><a href="#Ingredients" class="headerlink" title="Ingredients"></a>Ingredients</h2><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:right">Quantity</th>
<th>Ingredient</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">1 piece</td>
<td>Large brinjal</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">¼ tsp</td>
<td>Turmeric powder</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">a pinch</td>
<td>Red chilli powder</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">¾ tsp</td>
<td>Salt</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">1½ tsp</td>
<td>Sugar</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">¾ tsp</td>
<td>Flour (atta)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">~80 g</td>
<td>Mustard oil (for frying)</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="Equipment"><a href="#Equipment" class="headerlink" title="Equipment"></a>Equipment</h2><ul>
<li>Mixing bowl</li>
<li>Frying pan | skillet</li>
<li>Long spatula | <em>khunti</em> | fork </li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Appliances"><a href="#Appliances" class="headerlink" title="Appliances"></a>Appliances</h2><ul>
<li>Stove</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Method"><a href="#Method" class="headerlink" title="Method"></a>Method</h2><ol>
<li>Wash the brinjal and chop off its stalk. Cut the vegetable along the cross-section into discs, 2 cm thick. A large brinjal should yield about 6 slices.</li>
<li>In a mixing bowl, combine the turmeric powder, red chilli powder, salt, sugar, and <em>atta</em>.</li>
<li>Add the brinjal slices to the bowl and coat them with the spices.</li>
<li>Cover and let them rest for at least 15 minutes. During this time, the salt and sugar will draw out the water from the brinjal slices and soften them up. The moisture generated will also help all the flavours mingle nicely. So, don’t skip this step.</li>
<li>Now, heat mustard oil in a skillet till it starts smoking lightly. For even frying, the depth of the mustard oil in the pan should be at least 1 cm. </li>
<li>Lower the marinated brinjal slices into the oil one by one and fry them on each side, for about 3 minutes, till they are golden. Make sure that the pan is set on medium-low heat; we want to cook the brinjal slices from the inside while allowing them to develop a nice crust on the outside. Also, keep a close eye on the pan, as the sugar in the marinade may burn.</li>
<li>When golden, lift the <em>begun bhaja</em> from the oil. Hold them against the side of the pan for about 20 seconds to drain out excess oil, or use paper towels to soak it up. Serve hot.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="Served-with"><a href="#Served-with" class="headerlink" title="Served with"></a>Served with</h2><ul>
<li>Dal</li>
<li>Rice | <em>luchi</em></li>
</ul>
<script type="application/ld+json">
{
  "@context": "http://schema.org/",
  "@type": "Recipe",
  "name": "Begun Bhaja",
  "author": "Bong Eats",
  "image": "https://res.cloudinary.com/dmpeew57x/image/upload/v1481780296/begun-bhaja-thumbnail-small_dwcxsu.jpg",
  "description": "This is a recipe of brinjal fried to the an amber-coloured crisp on the outside, while remaining soft and mushy inside.",
  "prepTime": "PT5M",
  "totalTime": "PT20M",
  "recipeYield": "6 slices of begun bhaja",
  "recipeIngredient": [
    "Large brinjal  1 piece",
    "Turmeric powder ¼ tsp", 
    "Red chilli powder a pinch",
    "Salt  ¾ tsp",
    "Sugar 1½ tsp",
    "Flour (atta)  ¾ tsp",
    "Mustard oil (for frying)  80 g"
  ],
  "recipeInstructions": [
    "1. Wash the brinjal and chop off its stalk. Cut the vegetable along the cross-section into discs, 2 cm thick. A large brinjal should yield about 6 slices.",
    "2. In a mixing bowl, combine the turmeric powder, red chilli powder, salt, sugar, and atta.",
    "3. Add the brinjal slices to the bowl and coat them with the spices.",
    "4. Cover and let them rest for at least 15 minutes. During this time, the salt and sugar will draw out the water from the brinjal slices and soften them up. The moisture generated will also help all the flavours mingle nicely. So, don’t skip this step",
    "5. Now, heat mustard oil in a skillet till it starts smoking lightly. For even frying, the depth of the mustard oil in the pan should be at least 1 cm.", 
    "6. Lower the marinated brinjal slices into the oil one by one and fry them on each side, for about 3 minutes, till they are golden. Make sure that the pan is set on medium-low heat; we want to cook the brinjal slices from the inside while allowing them to develop a nice crust on the outside. Also, keep a close eye on the pan, as the sugar in the marinade may burn.",
    "7. When golden, lift the begun bhaja from the oil. Hold them against the side of the pan for about 20 seconds to drain out excess oil, or use paper towels to soak it up. Serve hot."
   ]
}
</script>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p class=&quot;post-byline&quot;&gt;The goodness of perfectly seasoned, pan-fried brinjals&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;post-intro&quot;&gt;This is a recipe of brinjal fried to an amber-coloured crust on the outside, while remaining soft and mushy inside.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="recipe" scheme="https://bongeats.com/categories/recipe/"/>
    
    
      <category term="vegetarian" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/vegetarian/"/>
    
      <category term="vegan" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/vegan/"/>
    
      <category term="bhaja" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/bhaja/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Jhinge Alu Posto</title>
    <link href="https://bongeats.com/recipe/jhinge-alu-posto/"/>
    <id>https://bongeats.com/recipe/jhinge-alu-posto/</id>
    <published>2016-12-22T17:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-12-30T04:20:12.826Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p class="post-byline">Potatoes and ridged gourd cooked in a poppy paste</p>

<p class="post-intro">Subtle to taste and mellowing in its effect, this classic preparation is the ultimate comfort food of the siesta-loving Bangali.</p>

<a id="more"></a>
<p><span class="dropcap">J</span><em>hinge-alu posto</em> is a classic Bengali dish. Sparing in its use of spices, this preparation relies on the flavours inherent in the vegetables (potatoes and ridged gourd) for its taste. What stands out, however, is the nutty flavour of the roasted poppy paste, which also provides body and texture to the gravy. Overall, the taste of this dish is so understated that it is difficult to imagine how its key ingredient, the poppy seed, was actually a residual by-product of the violent history, fraught with all manner of power imbalances and exploitation, of opium trade.</p><p></p>
<hr>
<p><strong>COOKING TIME</strong> 40 minutes<br><strong>YIELDS</strong> 4 servings</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="Ingredients"><a href="#Ingredients" class="headerlink" title="Ingredients"></a>Ingredients</h2><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:right">Quantity</th>
<th>Ingredient</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">15 g</td>
<td>Poppy seeds (soaked in water for at least 4 hours)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">4 pieces (2 for the paste + 2 for phoron)</td>
<td>Green chillies</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">40 g</td>
<td>Onions (cubed)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">25 g</td>
<td>Vegetable oil</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">¼ tsp</td>
<td>Kaalo jeere (nigella seeds)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">300 g</td>
<td>Potatoes (2 cm cubes)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">250 g</td>
<td>Jhinge or ridged gourd (2 cm cubes)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">10 g</td>
<td>Salt</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">8 g</td>
<td>Sugar</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">125 g</td>
<td>Warm water</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="Equipment"><a href="#Equipment" class="headerlink" title="Equipment"></a>Equipment</h2><ul>
<li>Frying pan | <em>kadai</em></li>
<li>Long spatula | <em>khunti</em></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Appliances"><a href="#Appliances" class="headerlink" title="Appliances"></a>Appliances</h2><ul>
<li>Stove</li>
<li>Grinder</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Method"><a href="#Method" class="headerlink" title="Method"></a>Method</h2><ol>
<li>Soak the poppy seeds in hot water for at least 4 hours. You can also soak them overnight in water at room temperature. </li>
<li>Drain the water and place the poppy seeds in a small grinder jar, along with 2 green chillies and cubed onions. </li>
<li>Grind these to a smooth paste, using about 50 g of water. The finer the grind, the better the flavour. So take your time with this step. Once done, set the poppy paste aside.</li>
<li>Heat 25 g vegetable oil in a pan. We don’t use mustard oil in this recipe to preserve the white colour of the dish.</li>
<li>Temper the oil with <em>kaalo jeere</em> and 2 slit green chillies.</li>
<li>Once the spices start crackling, add the cubed potatoes and fry them on medium heat for 4 minutes. The potatoes should not brown, but remain white. Stir them frequently. </li>
<li>Next, add in the <em>jhinge</em>. Fry them for another 4–5 minutes.</li>
<li>Now, add the poppy paste to the pan, along with the salt.</li>
<li>Sauté the vegetables in the poppy paste for around 5–7 minutes. Keep the heat on low and stir often to prevent the paste from sticking to the pan. </li>
<li>Once the poppy paste starts releasing a nutty aroma, add 125 g of hot water along with the sugar.</li>
<li>Let simmer on low heat for another 8–10 minutes, till the potatoes are tender and the gravy has thickened.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="Served-with"><a href="#Served-with" class="headerlink" title="Served with"></a>Served with</h2><ul>
<li>Dal</li>
<li>Rice | roti</li>
</ul>
<script type="application/ld+json">
{
  "@context": "http://schema.org/",
  "@type": "Recipe",
  "name": "Jhinge Alu Posto",
  "author": "Bong Eats",
  "image": "https://res.cloudinary.com/dmpeew57x/image/upload/v1481780300/jhinge-alu-posto-thumbnail-small_qcfwl0.jpg",
  "description": "Potatoes and ridged gourd cooked in a poppy paste",
  "prepTime": "PT10M",
  "totalTime": "PT40M",
  "recipeYield": "4",
  "recipeIngredient": [
    "Poppy seeds (soaked in hot water for at least 4 hours) 15 g",
    "Green chillies (2 for the paste + 2 for phoron) 4 pieces", 
    "Onions (cubed)  40 g",
    "Oil 25 g",
    "Kalo jeere  ¼ tsp",
    "Potatoes (2 cm cubes) 300 g",
    "Jhinge (2 cm cubes) 250 g",
    "Salt  10 g",
    "Sugar 8 g",
    "Warm water  125 g"
  ],
  "recipeInstructions": [
    "1. Soak the poppy seeds in hot water for at least 4 hours. You can also soak them overnight in water at room temperature.", 
    "2. Drain the water and place the poppy seeds in a small grinder jar, along with 2 green chillies and cubed onions.", 
    "3. Grind these to a smooth paste, using about 50 g of water. The finer the grind, the better the flavour. So take your time with this step. Once done, set the poppy paste aside.",
    "4. Heat 25 g vegetable oil in a pan. We don’t use mustard oil in this recipe.",
    "5. Temper the oil with _kaalo jeere_ and 2 slit green chillies.",
    "6. Once the spices start crackling, add in the cubed potatoes and fry them on medium heat for 4 minutes. The potatoes should not brown, but remain white. Stir them frequently.", 
    "7. Next, add in the _jhinge_. Fry them for another 4–5 minutes.",
    "8. Now, add the poppy paste to the pan, along with the salt.",
    "9. Sauté the vegetables in the poppy paste for around 5–7 minutes. Keep the heat on low and stir often to prevent the paste from sticking to the pan.", 
    "10. Once the poppy paste starts releasing a nutty aroma, add 125 g of hot water along with the sugar.",
    "11. Let simmer on low heat for another 8–10 minutes, till the potatoes are tender and the gravy has thickened."
   ]
}
</script>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p class=&quot;post-byline&quot;&gt;Potatoes and ridged gourd cooked in a poppy paste&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;post-intro&quot;&gt;Subtle to taste and mellowing in its effect, this classic preparation is the ultimate comfort food of the siesta-loving Bangali.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="recipe" scheme="https://bongeats.com/categories/recipe/"/>
    
    
      <category term="vegetarian" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/vegetarian/"/>
    
      <category term="vegan" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/vegan/"/>
    
      <category term="gluten-free" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/gluten-free/"/>
    
      <category term="torkari" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/torkari/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>How to Cook the Perfect Rice</title>
    <link href="https://bongeats.com/how-to/cook-the-perfect-rice/"/>
    <id>https://bongeats.com/how-to/cook-the-perfect-rice/</id>
    <published>2016-12-15T17:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-12-30T04:20:12.806Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p class="post-byline">A simple technique for that much-yearned-for <em>jhurjhure bhaat</em></p>

<p class="post-intro">In this tutorial, we show you how you can cook the perfect, fluffy, non-sticky rice on an everyday basis to go along with your <em>dal</em>, <em>torkari</em>, or <em>mangsher jhol</em> for the day.</p>

<a id="more"></a>
<p><span class="dropcap">R</span>ice is Bengal’s staple carbohydrate. Grown in vast quantities in paddy fields across the region, rice is eaten in various forms—boiled, steamed, puffed, or beaten. While the keeper of the Bengali kitchen might break out the precious <em>gobindobhog</em> for <em>polao</em>, <em>payesh</em>, or <em>khichuri</em>, and the <em>basmati</em> for <em>biryani</em>, it is the <em>sheddho chal</em>, or parboiled rice, that is piled onto plates daily. <em>Sheddho chal</em> is named after the technique used to separate the grain from the husk. This process is said to enhance the nutritional profile of the rice and make it easier to digest. </p>
<p>There is something extremely satisfying in sitting down to a meal before a plate of perfectly cooked, non-sticky, pearly-white, fluffy rice. While there are innumerable ways of boiling rice and there appears to be no set formula, keeping a few things in mind is useful. (1) Washing the rice thoroughly and repeatedly helps get rid of the starch that usually contributes to its stickiness. (2) Rice, like pasta, must be boiled in a large pot of water. The water must measure at least 5 times in volume than the volume of uncooked rice. Doing so dilutes the starch and ensures that most of it gets drained out at the end, along with the water. (3) Once the rice is cooked to the desired softness, use a large strainer to remove the excess water. Letting the rice sit in the boiled, starchy water (or not draining off as much of the liquid as possible) will yield a sticky, mushy end product. (4) Sometimes, the iron content in the water tends to produce yellowish rice. For fluffy, white rice, you may add a tablespoon of vinegar or a teaspoon of <em>fitkari</em> (alum) to the boiling pot. (5) Finally, as for boiling time, it will depend on the rice and water you use. Ours usually takes about 25 minutes. We highly recommend that you determine the cooking time for <em>your</em> rice. Once you’ve done that, set a timer whenever you put a pot to boil. When the timer goes off, all you need to do is drain out the water, and you have perfectly cooked rice every single time.      </p>
<hr>
<p><strong>TIME TAKEN</strong> 20 to 30 minutes, depending on the rice and water you use</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="Ingredients"><a href="#Ingredients" class="headerlink" title="Ingredients"></a>Ingredients</h2><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:right">Quantity</th>
<th>Ingredient</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">1 cup</td>
<td>Rice</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">5 cups</td>
<td>Water</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">1 tbsp</td>
<td>Vinegar (optional)</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="Equipment"><a href="#Equipment" class="headerlink" title="Equipment"></a>Equipment</h2><ul>
<li>Boiling pot | saucepan</li>
<li>Lid for the boiling vessel</li>
<li>Large strainer | colander</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Appliance"><a href="#Appliance" class="headerlink" title="Appliance"></a>Appliance</h2><ul>
<li>Stove</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Method"><a href="#Method" class="headerlink" title="Method"></a>Method</h2><ol>
<li>Measure out the rice and place it in a boiling vessel. </li>
<li>Fill the pot with water and wash the rice thoroughly to remove dirt and any excess starch. Rinse and repeat this process till the water runs clear. </li>
<li>Fill the pot with water once again and set it to boil, with the lid on. Rice is a starch that loves water. Be sure to boil it in sufficient water (at least 5 parts water to 1 part rice) if you want your rice to not be sticky.</li>
<li>For fluffy, pearly-white rice, you may also add 1 tbsp of vinegar or 1 tsp of <em>fitkari</em> (alum) to the pot.</li>
<li>Cook the rice till it is just done. Check by lifting a grain between your fingers and mashing it gently. Do not overcook if you want the rice grains to remain firm and separate.</li>
<li>Strain immediately over a colander and allow the water to drain off completely before serving.   </li>
</ol>
<script type="application/ld+json">
{
  "@context": "http://schema.org/",
  "@type": "recipe",
  "name": "How to Cook the Perfect Rice",
  "author": "Bong Eats",
  "image": "https://res.cloudinary.com/dmpeew57x/image/upload/v1481780294/bhaat-thumbnail-small_ll5eta.jpg",
  "description": "In this tutorial, we show you how you can cook the perfect, fluffy, non-sticky rice on an everyday basis to go along with your dal, torkari, or mangsher jhol for the day.",
  "prepTime": "PT05M",
  "totalTime": "PT30M",
  "recipeYield": "2",
  "nutrition": {
    "@type": "NutritionInformation",
    "servingSize": "2 servings",
    "calories": "206 calories",
    "fatContent": "0.4 g",
    "carbohydrateContent": "45 g",
    "cholesterolContent": "0 mg",
    "fiberContent": "0.6 g",
    "proteinContent": "4.3 g",
    "saturatedFatContent": "0.1 g",
    "sodiumContent": "1.6 mg",
    "sugarContent": "0.1 g"
  },
  "recipeIngredient": [
    "Rice",
    "Water",
    "Vinegar or fitkari (alum)"
  ],
  "recipeInstructions": [
    "1. Measure out the rice and place it in a boiling vessel.",
    "2. Fill the pot with water and wash the rice thoroughly to remove dirt and any excess starch. Rinse and repeat this process till the water runs clear.",
    "3. Fill the pot with water once again and set it to boil, with the lid on. Rice is a starch that loves water. Be sure to boil it in sufficient water (at least 5 parts water to 1 part rice) if you want your rice to not be sticky.",
    "4. For fluffy, pearly-white rice, you may also add 1 tbsp of vinegar or 1 tsp of fitkari (alum) to the pot.",
    "5. Cook the rice till it is just done. Check by lifting a grain between your fingers and mashing it gently. Do not overcook if you want the rice grains to remain firm and separate.",
    "6. Strain immediately over a colander and allow the water to drain off completely before serving."
   ]
}
</script>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p class=&quot;post-byline&quot;&gt;A simple technique for that much-yearned-for &lt;em&gt;jhurjhure bhaat&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;post-intro&quot;&gt;In this tutorial, we show you how you can cook the perfect, fluffy, non-sticky rice on an everyday basis to go along with your &lt;em&gt;dal&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;torkari&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;mangsher jhol&lt;/em&gt; for the day.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="how to" scheme="https://bongeats.com/categories/how-to/"/>
    
    
      <category term="kitchen hacks" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/kitchen-hacks/"/>
    
      <category term="how-to" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/how-to/"/>
    
      <category term="Rice" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/Rice/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Mughlai Porota</title>
    <link href="https://bongeats.com/recipe/mughlai-porota/"/>
    <id>https://bongeats.com/recipe/mughlai-porota/</id>
    <published>2016-12-09T06:30:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-12-30T04:20:12.841Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p class="post-byline">A layered, deep-fried pastry filled with egg and minced meat</p>

<p class="post-intro">Making this dish at home may seem like a daunting task. And we won’t lie, it does require a fair bit of planning. But for the <em>mughlai porota</em> aficionado, the pay-offs are enormous!</p>

<a id="more"></a>
<p><span class="dropcap">M</span><em>ughlai porota</em> is essentially a flaky flour pastry, filled with a mixture of beaten eggs, <em>keema</em>, spices, and seasoning. It differs from other stuffed <em>porotas</em> in that filling cooks inside the <em>porota</em>, and that it is layered.</p>
<p><em>Mughlai porota</em> can be made at home with a little bit of organisation. Plan for the following elements individually, and in this order:</p><p></p>
<ol>
<li><strong>The <em>keema</em></strong>—This is an important component of the filling. We like to use cooked mutton or beef <em>keema</em> (minced meat sautéed with onions, ginger, garlic, green chillies, turmeric, and <em>garam masala</em>). It needs to be prepared in advance.</li>
<li><strong>The dough</strong>—This will form the pastry within which the filling is enclosed. Be sure to knead the flour and set it to rest for at least 30 minutes.</li>
<li><strong>The filling</strong>—While your dough is resting, use this time to chop the onions, green chillies, ginger, and fresh coriander. Toast some peanuts and roughly crush them. Get the bread crumbs and salt out. Beat an egg in a bowl along with all the ingredients and your filling is ready to go!</li>
<li><strong>The sides</strong>—<em>Mughlai porota</em> is served with a cabin-style salad of cucumber, onion, and beet, <em>alu’r torkari</em>, chicken or mutton <em>kosha</em>, and some ketchup. If you want some or all of these sides, be sure to prepare them before your start making the <em>mughlai</em>.</li>
<li><strong>The <em>Mughlai porota</em></strong>—Now that the filling has been prepared, the sides are organised, and the dough has had time to rest, we are ready to bring all these elements together. See below for the full recipe.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>COOKING TIME</strong> 60 minutes<br><strong>YIELDS</strong> 1 <em>mughlai porota</em></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="Ingredients"><a href="#Ingredients" class="headerlink" title="Ingredients"></a>Ingredients</h2><p><strong>FOR THE POROTA/PASTRY</strong></p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:right">Quantity</th>
<th>Ingredient</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">75 g</td>
<td>Flour</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">1 g</td>
<td>Salt</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">1 g</td>
<td>Sugar</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">5 g</td>
<td>Oil</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">40 g</td>
<td>Warm water</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><strong>FOR THE FILLING</strong></p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:right">Quantity</th>
<th>Ingredient</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">1 piece</td>
<td>Egg (beaten)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">20 g</td>
<td>Keema (cooked mutton or beef keema)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">10 g</td>
<td>Onions (finely diced)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">2 g</td>
<td>Green chillies (finely chopped)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">2 g</td>
<td>Ginger (finely diced)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">3 g</td>
<td>Coriander (finely chopped)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">5 g</td>
<td>Peanuts (toasted and roughly chopped)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">10 g</td>
<td>Bread crumbs</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">2 g</td>
<td>Salt</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">~300 ml</td>
<td>Oil for frying</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="Equipment"><a href="#Equipment" class="headerlink" title="Equipment"></a>Equipment</h2><ul>
<li>Mixing bowl or dish</li>
<li>Rolling pin | large rolling surface</li>
<li>Frying pan</li>
<li>Frying spoon | <em>jhanjhri</em></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Appliances"><a href="#Appliances" class="headerlink" title="Appliances"></a>Appliances</h2><ul>
<li>Stove</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Method"><a href="#Method" class="headerlink" title="Method"></a>Method</h2><p><strong>PART I—KNEADING THE DOUGH</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Place the flour, salt, sugar, and 5 g oil in a mixing bowl, and distribute the ingredients evenly.</li>
<li>Add 40 g warm water to the bowl and knead the dough for 5 minutes.</li>
<li>Coat the dough with 2 tablespoons of oil, cover the bowl, and set aside for 30 minutes.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>PART II—PREPARING THE FILLING</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Finely dice the onions, and ginger, chop green chillies, and fresh coriander.</li>
<li>Toast the peanuts in a pan till they are lightly coloured, and chop them roughly.</li>
<li>Now, crack an egg in a bowl. Add in the cooked <em>keema</em>, onions, ginger, green chillies, coriander, peanuts, breads crumbs, and salt.</li>
<li>Beat till all the ingredients are well combined.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>PART III—ROLLING THE PASTRY</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Oil your rolling surface and rolling pin.</li>
<li>Place the dough on the surface and start rolling into a thin, rectangular sheet, about 2 mm thick, and 30 cm by 40 cm in dimension.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>PART IV—BRINGING IT ALL TOGETHER</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>In a frying pan, set over medium heat, pour vegetable oil till it reaches a height of about 3 cm from the bottom of the pan.    </li>
<li>While the oil is heating up, place the filling in the centre of the rolled dough.</li>
<li>Form an envelope by folding the sides of the rolled sheet inward, starting with the longer sides. Press down gently to seal.</li>
<li>Now, fold the shorter sides such that the you have a pocket of filling, securely enclosed within the pastry sheet.</li>
<li>Lower the <em>mughlai</em> into the hot oil and fry on both sides till golden brown. Occasionally pat it down with the frying spoon to make sure that the filling is cooked thoroughly.</li>
<li>Remove the <em>mughlai porota</em> from the oil and place it on a chopping board. The residual heat will cook the egg to perfect doneness. Cut it into square segments and serve while still warm.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="Served-with"><a href="#Served-with" class="headerlink" title="Served with"></a>Served with</h2><ul>
<li>Alu’r torkari</li>
<li>Mutton or chicken kosha</li>
<li>Cabin-style salad</li>
<li>Ketchup</li>
</ul>
<script type="application/ld+json">
{
  "@context": "http://schema.org/",
  "@type": "Recipe",
  "name": "Mughlai Porota",
  "author": "Bong Eats",
  "image": "https://res.cloudinary.com/dmpeew57x/image/upload/v1479339210/moghlai-porota_cover-small_decg0b.jpg",
  "description": "Making mughlai porota at home may seem like a daunting task. And we won't lie, it does require a fair bit of planning. But for the mughlai porota aficionado, the pay-offs are enormous!",
  "prepTime": "PT30M",
  "totalTime": "PT60M",
  "recipeYield": "1 porota",
  "recipeIngredient": [
    "Flour    75 g",
    "Salt    1 g",
    "Sugar    1 g",
    "Oil    5 g",
    "Water    40 g",
    "Egg    1 piece",
    "Keema    20 g",
    "Onions    10 g",
    "Green chillies    2 g",
    "Ginger    2 g",
    "Coriander    3 g",
    "Peanuts    5 g",
    "Bread crumbs    10 g",
    "Salt    2 g"
  ],
  "recipeInstructions": [
    "1. Place the flour, salt, sugar, and 5 g oil in a mixing bowl, and distribute the ingredients evenly.",
    "2. Add 40 g warm water to the bowl and knead the dough for 5 minutes.",
    "3. Coat the dough with 2 tablespoons of oil, cover the bowl, and set aside for 30 minutes.",
    "4. Finely chop the onions, ginger, green chillies, and fresh coriander.",
    "5. Toast the peanuts in a pan till they are lightly coloured, and chop them roughly.",
    "6. Now, crack an egg in a bowl. Add in the cooked _keema_, onions, ginger, green chillies, coriander, peanuts, breads crumbs, and salt.",
    "7. Beat till all the ingredients are well combined.",
    "8. Oil your rolling surface and rolling pin.",
    "9. Place the dough on the surface and start rolling into a thin, rectangular sheet, about 2 mm thick, and 30 cm by 40 cm in dimension.",
    "10. In a frying pan, set over medium heat, pour vegetable oil till it reaches a height of about 3 cm from the bottom of the pan.",
    "11. While the oil is heating up, place the filling in the centre of the rolled dough.",
    "12. Form an envelope by folding the sides of the rolled sheet inward, starting with the longer sides. Press down gently to seal.",
    "13. Now, fold the shorter sides such that the you have a pocket of filling, securely enclosed within the pastry sheet.",
    "14. Lower the _mughlai_ into the hot oil and fry on both sides till golden brown. Occasionally pat it down with the frying spoon to make sure that the filling is cooked thoroughly.",
    "15. Remove the _mughlai porota_ from the oil and place it on a chopping board. Let it rest for a while. The residual heat will cook the egg to perfect doneness. Cut it into square segments and serve while still warm."
   ]
}
</script>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p class=&quot;post-byline&quot;&gt;A layered, deep-fried pastry filled with egg and minced meat&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;post-intro&quot;&gt;Making this dish at home may seem like a daunting task. And we won’t lie, it does require a fair bit of planning. But for the &lt;em&gt;mughlai porota&lt;/em&gt; aficionado, the pay-offs are enormous!&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="recipe" scheme="https://bongeats.com/categories/recipe/"/>
    
    
      <category term="non-vegetarian" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/non-vegetarian/"/>
    
      <category term="snack" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/snack/"/>
    
      <category term="cabin food" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/cabin-food/"/>
    
      <category term="street food" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/street-food/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Badhakopi&#39;r Ghonto</title>
    <link href="https://bongeats.com/recipe/badhakopir-ghonto/"/>
    <id>https://bongeats.com/recipe/badhakopir-ghonto/</id>
    <published>2016-12-02T04:30:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-12-30T04:20:12.774Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p class="post-byline">A dry curry of cabbage</p>

<p class="post-intro">This is a beautifully spiced cabbage-and-peas preparation that is a little hot, a little sweet, and with hints of ginger, <em>ghee</em>, and <em>garam masala</em>.</p>

<a id="more"></a>
<p><span class="dropcap">B</span><em>adhakopi’r ghonto</em> is essentially prepared by steaming fine shreds of cabbage (about 2 mm wide) in their own moisture, which is drawn out with the help of salt. There are five important points to remember while cooking this dish—(1) The cabbage must be cut as finely as possible. Larger strips will not only take longer to cook, they will fail to give the <em>badhakopi’r ghonto</em> the desired texture; (2) Once you add the cabbage to the pan, don’t add any extra water; (3) Cook on low heat. This will ensure that the moisture extracted from the cabbage doesn’t evaporate too quickly and cause the cabbage to stick to the pan; (4) Always cover the pan with a lid. This will also prevent the moisture generated by the cabbage from evaporating too quickly; (5) Stir intermittently to prevent sticking.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>COOKING TIME</strong> 45 minutes<br><strong>YIELDS</strong> 6 servings</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="Ingredients"><a href="#Ingredients" class="headerlink" title="Ingredients"></a>Ingredients</h2><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:right">Quantity</th>
<th>Ingredient</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">15 g</td>
<td>Mustard oil</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">1 piece</td>
<td>Dried red chilli (whole)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">1 piece</td>
<td>Bay leaf (whole)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">1 piece</td>
<td>Cardamom (whole)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">1 piece</td>
<td>Clove (whole)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">1 piece</td>
<td>Cinnamon (whole)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">2 g (or ¼ tsp)</td>
<td>Cumin seeds</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">400 g</td>
<td>Cabbage (cut into thin shreds, 2 mm wide)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">100 g</td>
<td>Potatoes (diced; 3 cm cubes)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">50 g</td>
<td>Peas (shelled)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">30 g</td>
<td>Tomatoes (diced)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">75 g</td>
<td>Prawns (optional; shelled and deveined)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">20 g</td>
<td>Ginger paste</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">2 g</td>
<td>Cumin powder</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">1 g</td>
<td>Coriander powder</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">3 g</td>
<td>Turmeric powder</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">1 g</td>
<td>Red chilli powder</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">10 g</td>
<td>Salt</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">25 g</td>
<td>Sugar</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">4 g</td>
<td>Ghee</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">¼ tsp</td>
<td>Garam masala powder</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">2 pieces</td>
<td>Green chillies (slit)</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="Equipment"><a href="#Equipment" class="headerlink" title="Equipment"></a>Equipment</h2><ul>
<li><em>Kadai</em> | wok</li>
<li>Lid for cooking vessel</li>
<li><em>Khunti</em> | long spatula</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Appliances"><a href="#Appliances" class="headerlink" title="Appliances"></a>Appliances</h2><ul>
<li>Stove</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Method"><a href="#Method" class="headerlink" title="Method"></a>Method</h2><p><strong>PART I—CUTTING THE CABBAGE</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Cut the cabbage into the thinnest possible shreds that you can manage. To make this process easier, deal with the vegetable in sections of 5 cm each. Take a segment, one at a time, and shave off shreds along its cross-section with your knife. Take your time with the cutting, because the outcome of the dish will depend on this step. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wn3EUuW5S7s" target="_blank" rel="external">Watch this video, which shows you how to cut cabbage</a> for <em>badhakopi’r ghonto</em>.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>PART II—TEMPERING THE OIL (<em>PHORON</em>)</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Heat 15 g mustard oil in a pan till it begins to smoke.</li>
<li>Add the <em>phoron</em> (comprising the dried red chilli, bay leaf, cardamom, cinnamon, clove, and cumin seeds) to the oil.</li>
<li>Once the spices start crackling, add in the cubed potatoes.</li>
<li>Fry the potatoes for 3 minutes on low heat, with the lid on.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>PART III—SAUTEEING THE SPICES</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Make a paste by mixing together the ginger paste, cumin powder, coriander powder, turmeric powder, red chilli powder, and 80 g of water.</li>
<li>Add this mixture to the potatoes and cook on medium heat till the water dries off.</li>
<li>Add in the diced tomatoes and shelled peas.</li>
<li>Then, add another 80 g of water and sautee the spices till the water dries off.</li>
<li>Add a slit green chilli and cook with the lid on for another minute.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>PART IV—STEAMING THE CABBAGE</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Add the shredded cabbage to the pan, along with the salt.</li>
<li>Fold in the spices and cook on low heat with the lid on. The salt will start dehydrating the cabbage and drawing out its moisture.</li>
<li>Steam the cabbage on low heat, with the lid on, for 12 minutes, stirring intermittently. Keep an eye on the pan to ensure that the cabbage doesn’t stick to the bottom.</li>
<li>Add the sugar and cook for another 15 minutes, stirring intermittently. The sugar will soon start to caramelise. Be sure to scrape down and integrate the lightly browned bits of the <em>torkari</em> that stick to the bottom of your pan (they are yummy!).</li>
<li>This step is optional. You can coat a couple of cleaned prawns in a pinch of salt and turmeric powder, and fry in a separate pan for 30 seconds on each side. Chop the fried prawns in chunks of 1 cm, and add to the <em>ghonto</em>.</li>
<li>Garnish with <em>ghee</em>, powdered <em>garam masala</em>, and a  slit green chilli.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="Served-with"><a href="#Served-with" class="headerlink" title="Served with"></a>Served with</h2><ul>
<li>Dal</li>
<li>Rice | roti</li>
</ul>
<script type="application/ld+json">
{
  "@context": "http://schema.org/",
  "@type": "Recipe",
  "name": "Badhakopi'r ghonto",
  "author": "Bong Eats",
  "image": "https://res.cloudinary.com/dmpeew57x/image/upload/v1479339208/badhakopir-ghonto_cover-small_uif59l.jpg",
  "description": "This is a beautifully spiced cabbage and peas preparation that is hot, sweet, and with hints of ginger, ghee, and garam masala.",
  "prepTime": "PT10M",
  "totalTime": "PT45M",
  "recipeYield": "4",
  "recipeIngredient": [
    "Mustard oil (for cooking) 15 g",
    "Dried red chillies 1 piece",
    "Bay leaves 1 piece",
    "Cardamom 1 piece",
    "Cloves 1 piece",
    "Cinnamon 1 piece",
    "Cumin seeds 2 g (or ¼ tsp)",
    "Cabbage 400 g",
    "Potatoes 100 g",
    "Peas 50 g",
    "Tomatoes 30 g",
    "Prawns (optional) 75 g",
    "Ginger paste 20 g",
    "Cumin powder 2 g",
    "Coriander powder 1 g",
    "Turmeric powder 3 g",
    "Red chilli powder 1 g",
    "Salt 10 g",
    "Sugar 25 g",
    "Ghee 4 g",
    "Garam masala ¼ tsp",
    "Green chillies 2 g (or 2 pieces)"
  ],
  "recipeInstructions": [
    "1 Cut the cabbage into the thinnest possible shreds that you can manage. To make this process easier, deal with the vegetable in sections. Take out a 4cm-thick slice from the head of the cabbage and use your knife to shave off the shreds from the cross-section. The finer you cut the cabbage, the better. So, take your time at this stage.",
    "2 Heat 15g mustard oil in the pan.",
    "3 Add the phoron to the oil.",
    "4 Once the spices start crackling, add the cubed potatoes.",
    "5 Fry the potatoes for 3 minutes on low heat, with the lid on.",
    "6 Add 80g of water to the ginger paste, cumin powder, coriander powder, turmeric powder, and red chilli powder.",
    "7 Add this mixture to the potatoes and cook on medium heat till the water dries off.",
    "8 Add the diced tomatoes.",
    "9 Then, add another 80g of water and cook till the water dries off.",
    "10 Add the peas and a green chilli and cook with the lid on for a minute.",
    "11 Add the shredded cabbage to the pan, along with the salt.",
    "12 Fold in the spices and cook with the lid on. The salt we just added will start dehydrating the cabbage and drawing out its favours. We need this water to turn to steam and cook the cabbage, so it’s important to keep the lid on.",
    "13 Cook the cabbage on low heat, with the lid on, for 12 minutes, stirring intermittently. Keep an eye on the pan so that the cabbage doesn’t stick to the bottom.",
    "14 Add the sugar and cook for another 15 minutes, stirring intermittently. The sugar will start to caramelise. So, be sure to scrape the browned bits of the torkari that stick to the bottom of your pan.",
    "15 If adding the prawns: (a) Marinate them in ¼ tsp each of salt and turmeric powder; (b) Fry them in a separate pan for 30 seconds on each side; (c) Chop them up in 1-cm-small pieces; and (d) Add these to the torkari.",
    "16 Garnish with ghee, powdered garam masala, and a green chilli."
   ]
}
</script>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p class=&quot;post-byline&quot;&gt;A dry curry of cabbage&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;post-intro&quot;&gt;This is a beautifully spiced cabbage-and-peas preparation that is a little hot, a little sweet, and with hints of ginger, &lt;em&gt;ghee&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;garam masala&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="recipe" scheme="https://bongeats.com/categories/recipe/"/>
    
    
      <category term="vegetarian" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/vegetarian/"/>
    
      <category term="vegan" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/vegan/"/>
    
      <category term="gluten-free" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/gluten-free/"/>
    
      <category term="torkari" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/torkari/"/>
    
      <category term="ghonto" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/ghonto/"/>
    
      <category term="cabbage" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/cabbage/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Bengali Garam Masala</title>
    <link href="https://bongeats.com/recipe/bengali-garam-masala/"/>
    <id>https://bongeats.com/recipe/bengali-garam-masala/</id>
    <published>2016-11-25T04:30:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-11-23T01:57:26.193Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p class="post-byline">A fragrant blend of three simple spices</p>

<p class="post-intro"><em>Garam masala</em> is an important component of much of South Asian cooking. It is a blend of whole spices, whose proportions vary from cuisine to cuisine. The Bengali version comprises three simple spices—cardamom, cinnamon, and cloves.</p>

<a id="more"></a>
<p><span class="dropcap">W</span>hile the <em>garam masala</em> used in most northern and western Indian cooking might contain everything from coriander and cumin seeds to mustard seeds, the Bengali version, in its most basic form, is made up of cardamom, cinnamon, and cloves. The preparation is simple. We dry-roast a blend of the whole spices to awaken their dormant flavours and powder them—either by hand on in an electric grinder. If stored in an airtight container, the <em>masala</em> can keep for months.  </p>
<p>In Bengali cooking, <em>garam masala</em> is used to flavour egg, chicken, mutton, lamb, or beef curries. Along with <em>ghee</em>, it is also used as garnish for several vegetarian preparations (most <em>ghontos</em> and <a href="/tags/dalna/" title="Bengali dalna recipes"><em>dalnas</em></a>, <em>khichuri</em>, and <em>panchmishali torkari</em>). This spice is particularly handy if you want to quickly refresh leftovers. Just add a pinch of it (along with a sliver of <em>ghee</em>) to your day-old <em>torkari</em> while reheating, and no one need be any the wiser!</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>COOKING TIME</strong> 10 minutes<br><strong>YIELDS</strong> 10 g of <em>garam masala</em> powder</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="Ingredients"><a href="#Ingredients" class="headerlink" title="Ingredients"></a>Ingredients</h2><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:right">Quantity</th>
<th>Ingredient</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">7 g</td>
<td>Cardamom (whole)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">2 g</td>
<td>Cloves (whole)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">2 g</td>
<td>Cinnamon (whole)</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="Equipment"><a href="#Equipment" class="headerlink" title="Equipment"></a>Equipment</h2><ul>
<li><em>Kadai</em> | wok | frying pan</li>
<li><em>Khunti</em> | long spatula</li>
<li>Airtight container</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Appliances"><a href="#Appliances" class="headerlink" title="Appliances"></a>Appliances</h2><ul>
<li>Grinder | mortar and pestle</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Method"><a href="#Method" class="headerlink" title="Method"></a>Method</h2><ol>
<li>Measure out the whole spices in the given proportion. You may lightly crush them with a pestle or rolling pin before roasting, if you like.</li>
<li>Heat a pan on medium-low flame and add the whole spices to the pan.</li>
<li>Dry-roast them evenly on all sides, stirring continuously, for about 5 minutes. You should be able to smell the fragrance of the <em>garam masala</em> by this point.</li>
<li>Add the toasted spices to a grinder and blitz them till you have a fine powder. You can also use a mortar and pestle to grind by hand.</li>
<li>Store the <em>garam masala</em> powder in an airtight container.</li>
</ol>
<script type="application/ld+json">
{
  "@context": "http://schema.org/",
  "@type": "Recipe",
  "name": "Bengali garam masala",
  "author": "Bong Eats",
  "image": "https://res.cloudinary.com/dmpeew57x/image/upload/v1479358970/bengali-garam-masala-cover-small_r61kr3.jpg",
  "description": "The Bengali _garam masala_ contains just three simple ingredients.",
  "prepTime": "PT5M",
  "totalTime": "PT10M",
  "recipeYield": "10 g",
  "recipeIngredient": [
    "Cardamom 7    g",
    "Cloves 2    g",
    "Cinnamon 2 g"
  ],
  "recipeInstructions": [
    "1 Measure out the whole spices in the given proportion. You may lightly crush them with a pestle or rolling pin, if you like.",
    "2 Heat a pan on medium-low and add the whole spices.",
    "3 Dry-roast them evenly on all sides, stirring continuously. This should take about 5 minutes.",
    "4 Add the toasted spices to a grinder and blitz them till you have a fine powder. You can also use a mortar and pestle.",
    "5 Store the garam masala powder in an airtight container for up to 2 months."
   ]
}
</script>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p class=&quot;post-byline&quot;&gt;A fragrant blend of three simple spices&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;post-intro&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Garam masala&lt;/em&gt; is an important component of much of South Asian cooking. It is a blend of whole spices, whose proportions vary from cuisine to cuisine. The Bengali version comprises three simple spices—cardamom, cinnamon, and cloves.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="recipe" scheme="https://bongeats.com/categories/recipe/"/>
    
    
      <category term="masala" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/masala/"/>
    
      <category term="vegetarian" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/vegetarian/"/>
    
      <category term="vegan" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/vegan/"/>
    
      <category term="gluten-free" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/gluten-free/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>How to Clean and Devein Prawns</title>
    <link href="https://bongeats.com/how-to/clean-and-devein-prawns/"/>
    <id>https://bongeats.com/how-to/clean-and-devein-prawns/</id>
    <published>2016-11-18T05:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-11-17T05:55:17.035Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p class="post-byline">A step-by-step guide to prepping your prawns</p>

<p class="post-intro">In this tutorial, we show you how to go about cleaning a batch of prawns. It’s not as difficult as you imagine.</p>

<a id="more"></a>
<p><span class="dropcap">C</span>leaning prawns doesn’t have to be a tedious or messy task. With a bit of organisation, you can get a batch done in no time, and with minimal cleaning-up to do after. As for tools, all you need is a pair of scissors. Apart from that, keep a bin or plastic bag ready to catch the discarded shells and a bowl for the clean prawns. Put on a playlist, podcast, or audiobook of your choice. This last step is optional, but you might as well be entertained while cleaning up some crustacean.</p>
<p>Now, coming to the anatomy of the prawn, consider the parts you want to keep, and those you want to throw away. We usually eat fleshy bits, and discard the shells and other scalier parts. For most Bengali dishes, including <em>chingri malai curry</em> and <em>chingri bhaape</em>, we leave the head and tail of the prawn intact—the head contains all the wonderful flavour and tasty, creamy goodness, while the tail adds a nice presentation detail.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>TIME TAKEN</strong> 20 minutes for 500 g of prawns</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="Ingredients"><a href="#Ingredients" class="headerlink" title="Ingredients"></a>Ingredients</h2><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:right">Quantity</th>
<th>Ingredient</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">500 g</td>
<td>Prawns</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="Equipment"><a href="#Equipment" class="headerlink" title="Equipment"></a>Equipment</h2><ul>
<li>A pair of scissors</li>
<li>A dish or bag for scraps</li>
<li>A bowl or plate for clean prawns</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Things-to-remove"><a href="#Things-to-remove" class="headerlink" title="Things to remove"></a>Things to remove</h2><ul>
<li>The snout</li>
<li>The eyes</li>
<li>The walking legs</li>
<li>The shell</li>
<li>The vein</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Things-to-keep"><a href="#Things-to-keep" class="headerlink" title="Things to keep"></a>Things to keep</h2><ul>
<li>The body or the fleshy part</li>
<li>The head (for flavour and taste)</li>
<li>The tail (for presentation)</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Method"><a href="#Method" class="headerlink" title="Method"></a>Method</h2><ol>
<li>Use your scissors and cut off the snout, which is located on the head of the prawn, between the eyes.</li>
<li>Next, snip off the eyes.</li>
<li>Gather together all the walking legs (can be found under the head) and snip them off with your scissors as well.</li>
<li>Now, hold the prawn so that its head faces you, and its dorsal side is pointed upward. Cut through the shell along the (non-existent) spine of the prawn, from the head all the way to the tail.</li>
<li>You should now be able to peel off the shell. If it gets stuck anywhere, give it a tug and it should come loose easily.</li>
<li>Locate the vein along the spine of the prawn.</li>
<li>Pull the vein out and discard it.</li>
<li>You should now have a clean prawn, minus the shells and other pointy parts.</li>
<li>This step is optional, but we don’t throw the scraps away. Place them in a pot of water and simmer for 30 minutes. Strain the liquid and you now have a shrimp stock. Freeze them in ice trays and use the stock cubes  while making shrimp fried rice or <em>chingri malai curry</em> for instant flavour-boost.  </li>
</ol>
<script type="application/ld+json">
{
  "@context": "http://schema.org/",
  "@type": "recipe",
  "name": "How to clean and devein prawns",
  "author": "Bong Eats",
  "image": "https://res.cloudinary.com/dmpeew57x/image/upload/v1479339208/cleaning-chingri-cover-small_henyxp.jpg",
  "description": "In this tutorial, we show you how to go about cleaning a batch of prawns. It's not as difficult as you imagine.",
  "prepTime": "PT20M",
  "totalTime": "PT20M",
  "recipeIngredient": [
    "Prawns",
    "A pair of scissors",
    "A dish or bag for scraps",
    "A bowl or plate for clean prawns"
  ],
  "recipeInstructions": [
    "1 Use your scissors and cut off the snout.",
    "2 Next, snip off the eyes.",
    "3 Now, gather all the walking legs (can be found under the head) and chop them off with the scissors.",
    "4 Hold the prawn so that its head faces you, and with its convex side up. Cut through the shell along the spine of the prawn, from the head all the way to the tail.",
    "5 You should now be able to peel off the shell. If it gets stuck anywhere, give it a tug and it should come loose easily.",
    "6 Locate the vein along the spine of the prawn. You will find it on the same side where you cut through the shell.",
    "7 Pull the vein out and discard it.",
    "8 You should now have a clean prawn without the shells and other pointy parts. You can either cook them immediately, or store the rest in the freezer in a tiffin box or plastic bag for up to two weeks.",
    "9 This step is optional: don't throw the scraps away. Place them in a pot of water and boil for 30 minutes. Strain the liquid and you now have a shrimp stock. Store it in the refrigerator and use it while making shrimp fried rice or chingri malai curry for added flavour."
   ]
}
</script>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p class=&quot;post-byline&quot;&gt;A step-by-step guide to prepping your prawns&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;post-intro&quot;&gt;In this tutorial, we show you how to go about cleaning a batch of prawns. It’s not as difficult as you imagine.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="how to" scheme="https://bongeats.com/categories/how-to/"/>
    
    
      <category term="prawns" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/prawns/"/>
    
      <category term="fish" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/fish/"/>
    
      <category term="kitchen hacks" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/kitchen-hacks/"/>
    
      <category term="how-to" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/how-to/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Chingri Bhaape</title>
    <link href="https://bongeats.com/recipe/chingri-bhaape/"/>
    <id>https://bongeats.com/recipe/chingri-bhaape/</id>
    <published>2016-11-11T05:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-11-16T23:41:47.678Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p class="post-byline">Prawns steamed in a spicy mustard paste</p>

<p class="post-intro">Cooks in minutes and posh to look at, this is a potent curry, not for the faint of heart.</p>

<a id="more"></a>
<p><span class="dropcap">C</span><em>hingri bhaape</em> is a divine treat, and yet, it is ridiculously simple to make. It incorporates the rich flavours of freshly ground mustard, mellowed down with some coconut and yoghurt. While traditionally this dish has always been prepared in a steamer or double-boiler over a stove, we’ve used a microwave in this recipe.</p>
<p>This is an ideal dish to have on the menu if you are having guests over. You can prepare most of it (till Step 10 below) ahead of time, and steam the prawns in the microwave oven when the guests are ready to eat.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>COOKING TIME</strong> 30 minutes<br><strong>YIELDS</strong> 4 servings</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="Ingredients"><a href="#Ingredients" class="headerlink" title="Ingredients"></a>Ingredients</h2><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:right">Quantity</th>
<th>Ingredient</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">300 g</td>
<td>Shelled and deveined prawns (400 g before cleaning)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">20 g</td>
<td>Mustard seeds (soaked overnight in water)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">20 g</td>
<td>Coconut (chopped)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">4 pieces</td>
<td>Green chillies (3 chopped + 1 slit)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">40 g</td>
<td>Yoghurt</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">3 g</td>
<td>Turmeric powder</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">12 g</td>
<td>Salt</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">15 g</td>
<td>Sugar</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">25 g</td>
<td>Mustard oil</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="Equipment"><a href="#Equipment" class="headerlink" title="Equipment"></a>Equipment</h2><ul>
<li>Scissors | knife (for shelling and deveining the prawns)</li>
<li>Microwaveable bowl (preferably ceramic)</li>
<li>Plastic wrap</li>
<li>Water-tight metal container (optional; if not using a microwave)</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Appliances"><a href="#Appliances" class="headerlink" title="Appliances"></a>Appliances</h2><ul>
<li>Grinder</li>
<li>Microwave oven</li>
<li>Stove (optional; if not using a microwave)</li>
<li>Pressure cooker | boiling pot with lid (optional; if not using a microwave)</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Method"><a href="#Method" class="headerlink" title="Method"></a>Method</h2><ol>
<li>Soak the mustard seeds in hot water for at least 2 hours. Alternatively, you can also soak them in regular water, overnight.</li>
<li>Shell and devein the prawns. Keep the heads intact; they have all the flavour. The tails add a visual flair, so we keep them as well.</li>
<li>Strain the mustard seeds and add to a grinder jar, along with the salt and 3 green chillies.</li>
<li>Blitz into a fine paste with the help of 50 g water. Scrape down the sides as often as you need, and grind again. Repeat this process till you have a smooth paste.</li>
<li>Now, while the mustard paste is still in the grinder, add the sugar, turmeric powder, and chopped coconut. Blitz again till the coconut breaks down.</li>
<li>Transfer this paste to a microwave-safe bowl.</li>
<li>Add in the yoghurt and mix till uniform.</li>
<li>Fold in the prawns.</li>
<li>Top off with mustard oil and a slit green chilli.</li>
<li>Cover the bowl with a plastic wrap.</li>
<li>Microwave for 5 minutes.</li>
<li>IF YOU ARE NOT USING A MICROWAVE OVEN, place the prawns-and-mustard mixture in a covered steel container (such as a water-tight tiffin box). Bring an inch of water to boil in your pressure cooker or boiling pot. Now, carefully lower the tiffin box in the water. Be sure to check that the water level does not does not reach the lid of your tiffin box. If it does, throw away some of the water till it clears the lid. Cover up the pot/pressure cooker and allow the prawns to steam (for 10–12 minutes in the boiling pot OR for one whistle in a pressure cooker).  </li>
</ol>
<h2 id="Served-with"><a href="#Served-with" class="headerlink" title="Served with"></a>Served with</h2><ul>
<li>Rice</li>
</ul>
<script type="application/ld+json">
{
  "@context": "http://schema.org/",
  "@type": "Recipe",
  "name": "Chingri bhaape",
  "author": "Bong Eats",
  "image": "https://res.cloudinary.com/dmpeew57x/image/upload/v1478835725/thumbs/chingri-bhaape_thumbnail_small.jpg",
  "description": "This is a potent curry of steamed prawns, not for the faint of heart.",
  "prepTime": "PT25M",
  "totalTime": "PT30M",
  "recipeYield": "4",
  "recipeIngredient": [
    "Prawns 300 g (400 g before cleaning)",
    "Mustard seeds 20 g",
    "Coconut 20 g",
    "Green chillies 4 pieces",
    "Yoghurt 40 g",
    "Turmeric powder 3 g",
    "Salt 12 g",
    "Sugar 15 g",
    "Mustard oil 25 g"
  ],
  "recipeInstructions": [
    "1 Soak the mustard seeds in water for at least 2 hours.",
    "2 Shell and devein the prawns.",
    "3 Drain the mustard seeds and add to a grinder jar, along with the salt and 3 green chillies.",
    "4 Blitz into a fine paste with the help of 50g water. Open the lid, scrape down the sides, and grind again. Repeat this process till you have a fine paste.",
    "5 Add the sugar, turmeric powder, and chopped coconut into the grinder and blitz again till the coconut breaks down.",
    "6 Transfer this paste to a microwaveable bowl.",
    "7 Add the yoghurt and mix together.",
    "8 Add the prawns and fold in.",
    "9 Top off with the mustard oil and a slit green chilli.",
    "10 Cover the bowl with a plastic wrap.",
    "11 Microwave for 5 minutes."
   ]
}
</script>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p class=&quot;post-byline&quot;&gt;Prawns steamed in a spicy mustard paste&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;post-intro&quot;&gt;Cooks in minutes and posh to look at, this is a potent curry, not for the faint of heart.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="recipe" scheme="https://bongeats.com/categories/recipe/"/>
    
    
      <category term="prawns" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/prawns/"/>
    
      <category term="fish" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/fish/"/>
    
      <category term="mustard" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/mustard/"/>
    
      <category term="non-vegetarian" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/non-vegetarian/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Phulkopi&#39;r Dalna</title>
    <link href="https://bongeats.com/recipe/phulkopir-dalna/"/>
    <id>https://bongeats.com/recipe/phulkopir-dalna/</id>
    <published>2016-07-29T04:39:47.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-11-11T03:47:09.014Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p class="post-byline">A spicy cauliflower curry</p>

<p class="post-intro">A curry of cauliflower, potatoes, and peas that is a little hot, a little sweet, with hints of ginger, <em>ghee</em>, and <em>garam masala</em>.</p>

<a id="more"></a>
<p><span class="dropcap">B</span>engalis generally eat this beautifully spiced curry of cauliflower in the winter months, when the vegetable is harvested in large numbers. For this recipe, the cauliflower must be cut into chunky florets (about 5 cm large). Remember that the flavour is contained in the stem, so try to retain as much of it as possible. The florets are cooked twice—first stir-fried over medium heat to release some of their flavour, and then again with the spices and gravy. Even after all the frying and boiling, each cauliflower floret should hold its shape. It should snap when you run a knife through its stalk, and not disintegrate at touch from over-boiling.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>COOKING TIME</strong>  40 minutes<br><strong>YIELDS</strong> 4 servings</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="Ingredients"><a href="#Ingredients" class="headerlink" title="Ingredients"></a>Ingredients</h2><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:right">Sl</th>
<th style="text-align:right">Quantity</th>
<th>Ingredient</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right"></td>
<td style="text-align:right"><strong>OIL</strong></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">1</td>
<td style="text-align:right">30 g</td>
<td>Mustard oil (for frying)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">2</td>
<td style="text-align:right">10 g</td>
<td>Mustard oil (for cooking)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right"></td>
<td style="text-align:right"><strong><em>PHORON</em> (TEMPERING)</strong></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">3</td>
<td style="text-align:right">2 pieces</td>
<td>Dried red chillies (whole)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">4</td>
<td style="text-align:right">2 pieces</td>
<td>Bay leaves (whole)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">5</td>
<td style="text-align:right">3 pieces</td>
<td>Cardamom (whole)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">6</td>
<td style="text-align:right">3 pieces</td>
<td>Cloves (whole)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">7</td>
<td style="text-align:right">1 piece</td>
<td>Cinnamon (whole)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">8</td>
<td style="text-align:right">1 g (or ¼ tsp)</td>
<td>Cumin seeds (whole)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right"></td>
<td style="text-align:right"><strong>VEGETABLES</strong></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">9</td>
<td style="text-align:right">500 g</td>
<td>Cauliflower (cut in large florets)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">10</td>
<td style="text-align:right">250 g</td>
<td>Potatoes (diced; 5 cm cubes)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">11</td>
<td style="text-align:right">50 g</td>
<td>Peas (shelled)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">12</td>
<td style="text-align:right">50 g</td>
<td>Tomatoes (diced)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right"></td>
<td style="text-align:right"><strong>SPICES AND SEASONING</strong></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">13</td>
<td style="text-align:right">30 g</td>
<td>Ginger paste</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">14</td>
<td style="text-align:right">5 g</td>
<td>Cumin powder</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">15</td>
<td style="text-align:right">1 g</td>
<td>Coriander powder</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">16</td>
<td style="text-align:right">5 g</td>
<td>Turmeric powder</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">17</td>
<td style="text-align:right">1 g</td>
<td>Red chilli powder</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">18</td>
<td style="text-align:right">16 g</td>
<td>Salt</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">19</td>
<td style="text-align:right">28 g</td>
<td>Sugar</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right"></td>
<td style="text-align:right"><strong>GARNISH</strong></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">20</td>
<td style="text-align:right">7 g</td>
<td>Ghee</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">21</td>
<td style="text-align:right">½ tsp</td>
<td>Garam masala powder</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">22</td>
<td style="text-align:right">2 g (or 2 pieces)</td>
<td>Green chillies (slit)</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="Equipment"><a href="#Equipment" class="headerlink" title="Equipment"></a>Equipment</h2><ul>
<li><em>Kadai</em> | wok | frying pan | cooking pot</li>
<li>Lid for cooking vessel</li>
<li><em>Khunti</em> | long spatula</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Appliances"><a href="#Appliances" class="headerlink" title="Appliances"></a>Appliances</h2><ul>
<li>Stove</li>
<li>Electric kettle (optional)</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Method"><a href="#Method" class="headerlink" title="Method"></a>Method</h2><p><strong>PART I—FRYING THE CAULIFLOWER</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Cut the cauliflower in large florets, about 5 cm large.</li>
<li>Heat 30 g mustard oil in the pan.</li>
<li>Stir-fry the cauliflower for 5–7 minutes on medium-high heat till they develop a light amber colour.</li>
<li><p>Remove the cauliflower from the pan and reserve for later use.</p>
<p><strong>PART II—TEMPERING THE OIL</strong></p>
</li>
<li>Now, heat 10 g mustard oil in the same pan.</li>
<li>Add all the <em>phoron</em> (dried red chillies, bay leaves, cardamom, cinnamon, cloves, and cumin seeds) into the oil.</li>
<li>Once the whole spices start crackling, add the cubed potatoes.</li>
<li><p>Fry the potatoes for 5 minutes on low heat.</p>
<p><strong>PART III—SAUTEEING THE SPICES</strong></p>
</li>
<li>In a small bowl, make a spice paste by adding 100 g of water to ginger paste, cumin powder, coriander powder, turmeric powder, and red chilli powder.</li>
<li>Add this mixture to the pan and cook on medium heat till the water dries off.</li>
<li>Add the salt, sugar, and another 100 g of water, and cook till the water dries off again.</li>
<li>Add the diced tomatoes and a slit green chilli.</li>
<li>Once the tomatoes have assimilated into the spice mix, add in the peas and fried cauliflower.</li>
<li><p>Cook the vegetables on low heat, with the lid on, for 3 minutes.</p>
<p><strong>PART IV—PREPARING THE GRAVY</strong></p>
</li>
<li>Add 400 g hot water to the pan.</li>
<li>Cook the potatoes and cauliflower with the lid on for 10 minutes till the cauliflower stalks are tender. They should snap when you run a knife through them, but the florets should not disintegrate from over-boiling.</li>
<li>Garnish with ghee, garam masala powder, and a slit green chilli.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="Served-with"><a href="#Served-with" class="headerlink" title="Served with"></a>Served with</h2><ul>
<li>Dal</li>
<li>Rice | <em>rooti</em></li>
</ul>
<script type="application/ld+json">
{
  "@context": "http://schema.org/",
  "@type": "Recipe",
  "name": "Phulkopi'r dalna",
  "author": "Bong Eats",
  "image": "https://res.cloudinary.com/dmpeew57x/image/upload/v1478835833/thumbs/phulkopir-dalna-thumbnail-small.jpg",
  "description": "A curry of cauliflower, potatoes, and peas that is a little hot, a little sweet, and with hints of ginger, ghee, and garam masala.",
  "prepTime": "PT10M",
  "totalTime": "PT40M",
  "recipeYield": "4",
  "recipeIngredient": [
    "Mustard oil (for frying)    30 g",
    "Mustard oil (for cooking)    10 g",
    "Dried red chillies    2 pieces",
    "Bay leaves    2 pieces",
    "Cardamom    3 pieces",
    "Cloves    3 pieces",
    "Cinnamon    1 piece",
    "Cumin seeds    2 g (or ¼ tsp)",
    "Cauliflower    500 g",
    "Potatoes    250 g",
    "Peas    50 g",
    "Tomatoes    50 g",
    "Ginger paste    30 g",
    "Cumin powder    5 g",
    "Coriander powder    1 g",        
    "Turmeric powder    5 g",
    "Red chilli powder    1 g",
    "Salt    16 g",
    "Sugar    28 g",        
    "Ghee    7 g",            
    "Garam masala    powder 1/2 tsp",        
    "Green chillies    2 g (or 2 pieces)"
  ],
  "recipeInstructions": [
    "1. Cut the cauliflower in large florets, about 5 cm large.",
    "2. Heat 30 g mustard oil in the pan.",
    "3. Stir-fry the cauliflower for 5–7 minutes on medium-high heat till they develop a light amber colour.",
    "4. Remove the cauliflower from the pan and reserve for later use.",
    "5. Now, heat 10 g mustard oil in the same pan.",
    "6. Add all the phoron into the oil.",
    "7. Once the whole spices start crackling, add the cubed potatoes.",
    "8. Fry the potatoes for 5 minutes on low heat.",
    "9. Add 100 g of water to the ginger paste, cumin powder, coriander powder, turmeric powder, and red chilli powder.",
    "10. Add this mixture to the pan and cook on medium heat till the water dries off.",
    "11. Add the salt, sugar, and another 100 g of water and cook till the water dries off.",
    "12. Add the diced tomatoes and a green chilli.",
    "13. Once the tomatoes have assimilated, add the peas and fried cauliflower.",
    "14. Cook with the lid on for 3 minutes, on low heat.",
    "15. Add 500 g hot water to the pan.",
    "16. Cook the potatoes and cauliflower with the lid on for 10 minutes till the cauliflower stalks are tender. They should snap when you run a knife through them, but the florets should not disintegrate from over-boiling.",
    "17. Garnish with ghee, powdered garam masala, and a green chilli."
   ]
}
</script>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p class=&quot;post-byline&quot;&gt;A spicy cauliflower curry&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;post-intro&quot;&gt;A curry of cauliflower, potatoes, and peas that is a little hot, a little sweet, with hints of ginger, &lt;em&gt;ghee&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;garam masala&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="recipe" scheme="https://bongeats.com/categories/recipe/"/>
    
    
      <category term="vegetarian" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/vegetarian/"/>
    
      <category term="vegan" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/vegan/"/>
    
      <category term="gluten-free" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/gluten-free/"/>
    
      <category term="dalna" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/dalna/"/>
    
      <category term="curry" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/curry/"/>
    
      <category term="torkari" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/torkari/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Plain Mosur Dal</title>
    <link href="https://bongeats.com/recipe/plain-mosur-dal/"/>
    <id>https://bongeats.com/recipe/plain-mosur-dal/</id>
    <published>2016-07-29T04:39:47.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-11-11T03:47:30.407Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p class="post-byline">A light dal made of orange lentils</p>

<p class="post-intro">This hearty dal goes well with almost any <em>bhaja</em> or <em>torkari</em>. Because it is sparsely spiced, it doesn’t overpower other dishes. Rather, it steps back and lets its partners-in-course shine.</p>

<a id="more"></a>
<p><span class="dropcap">W</span>hile it might be the nutty aroma of dry-roasted <em>moong</em> dal that often transports you back to your childhood home, this plain <em>mosur</em> dal, uplifted with the flavour of chopped coriander leaves at the end, is what you want to cook at the end of a weekend of revelry and binge-eating. On those distraught Sunday evenings when you cannot bring yourself to face the hard truth of going back to work the next morning, spend 20 minutes making this simple <em>mosur</em> dal. As the dal is boiling, start cooking some rice. While you are at it, throw in a small potato (halved) into the pot of rice. At the end of those 20 minutes you will have steamed rice, dal, and alu sheddho. Make yourself a hot omelette, if you care. Squeeze a dash of lime on your dal. You now have a meal so comforting, it will have numbed all your pain.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>COOKING TIME</strong> 20 minutes<br><strong>YIELDS</strong> 5 servings</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="Ingredients"><a href="#Ingredients" class="headerlink" title="Ingredients"></a>Ingredients</h2><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:right">Quantity</th>
<th>Ingredient</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">15 g</td>
<td>Mustard oil</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">¼ tsp</td>
<td>Kaalo jeere or nigella seeds</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">2 pieces</td>
<td>Dried red chillies</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">2 pieces</td>
<td>Green chillies (slit)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">1 piece</td>
<td>Bay leaf</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">½ tsp (or 1 g)</td>
<td>Turmeric powder</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">8 g</td>
<td>Salt</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">500 g</td>
<td>Water</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">100 g</td>
<td>Mosur dal</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">6 g</td>
<td>Coriander leaves (finely chopped)</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="Equipment"><a href="#Equipment" class="headerlink" title="Equipment"></a>Equipment</h2><ul>
<li>Boiling pot | pressure cooker</li>
<li>Beater | balloon whisk | fork | <em>dal’er kaanta</em></li>
<li>Frying pan | saucepan | <em>kadai</em></li>
<li>Ladle | large spoon</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Appliances"><a href="#Appliances" class="headerlink" title="Appliances"></a>Appliances</h2><ul>
<li>Stove</li>
<li>Pressure cooker (optional)</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Method"><a href="#Method" class="headerlink" title="Method"></a>Method</h2><ol>
<li>Wash the dal thoroughly with plenty of water, making sure to rinse and repeat at least twice.</li>
<li>Place the washed and drained dal in a pressure cooker with 500 g of water. You can also cook the dal over the stove in a lidded pot, but make sure to take 600 g of water instead of 500 g to compensate for evaporation.</li>
<li>Boil till you see the broken grains of dal. If using a pressure cooker, cook on medium-high heat till you hear the first whistle. Turn off the heat and let the pressure release on its own.</li>
<li>Whisk the boiled dal with a beater till you can no longer see the individual grains.</li>
<li>Now, heat up your <em>kadai</em>.</li>
<li>Add mustard oil and allow it to smoke lightly.</li>
<li>Temper the oil with <em>kaalo jeere</em>, dried red chillies, green chillies, and bay leaf, till the spices crackle.</li>
<li>Add in the whisked dal.</li>
<li>Add turmeric and salt.</li>
<li>Allow the dal to boil on medium heat for 4–5 minutes.</li>
<li>Garnish with the chopped coriander leaves. Boil for another minute and remove from heat.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="Served-with"><a href="#Served-with" class="headerlink" title="Served with"></a>Served with</h2><ul>
<li><em>Bhaja</em> | <em>torkari</em></li>
<li>Rice</li>
</ul>
<script type="application/ld+json">
{
  "@context": "http://schema.org/",
  "@type": "Recipe",
  "name": "Plain mosur dal",
  "author": "Bong Eats",
  "image": "https://res.cloudinary.com/dmpeew57x/image/upload/v1478835725/thumbs/plain-mosur-dal_thumbnail_small.jpg",
  "description": "This is one of the simplest dals you can make. It is light and hearty, and goes well with almost any bhaja or torkari. Because it is sparsely spiced, it is a perfect component of a day-to-day meal.",
  "prepTime": "PT10M",
  "totalTime": "PT20M",
  "recipeYield": "5",
  "recipeIngredient": [
    "Mustard oil    15 g",
    "Kaalo jeere    ¼ tsp",
    "Dried red chillies    2 pcs",
    "Green chillies    2 pcs",
    "Bay leaf    1 pc",
    "Turmeric powder    ½ tsp (or 1 g)",
    "Salt    8 g",
    "Water    500 g",
    "Coriander leaves 6 g",
    "Mosur dal    100 g"
  ],
  "recipeInstructions": [
    "1 Rinse the dal well and drain the water",
    "2 Place washed dal in a pressure cooker with 500g water",
    "3 Boil till you see the broken grains of dal. If using a pressure cooker, cook on medium-high heat till you hear the first whistle. Turn off the heat and let the pressure release on its own",
    "4 Whisk the boiled dal till you can no longer see the individual grains",
    "5 Heat up your pan",
    "6 Add mustard oil and allow it to smoke lightly",
    "7 Add kaalo jeere, dried red chillies, green chillies, and bay leaf",
    "8 Add the whisked dal",
    "9 Add turmeric and salt",
    "10 Allow it to boil on medium heat for 4–5 minutes",
    "11 Garnish with the chopped coriander"
   ]
}
</script>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p class=&quot;post-byline&quot;&gt;A light dal made of orange lentils&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;post-intro&quot;&gt;This hearty dal goes well with almost any &lt;em&gt;bhaja&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;torkari&lt;/em&gt;. Because it is sparsely spiced, it doesn’t overpower other dishes. Rather, it steps back and lets its partners-in-course shine.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="recipe" scheme="https://bongeats.com/categories/recipe/"/>
    
    
      <category term="vegetarian" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/vegetarian/"/>
    
      <category term="vegan" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/vegan/"/>
    
      <category term="gluten-free" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/gluten-free/"/>
    
      <category term="dal" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/dal/"/>
    
      <category term="mosur dal" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/mosur-dal/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Alu Sheddho</title>
    <link href="https://bongeats.com/recipe/alu-sheddho/"/>
    <id>https://bongeats.com/recipe/alu-sheddho/</id>
    <published>2016-07-29T04:39:47.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-11-11T03:44:16.959Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p class="post-byline">Boiled potatoes, flavoured with green chillies and a fat of your choice</p>

<p class="post-intro">This is the Bengali version of the mashed potato in its most basic form. It is made up of just four simple ingredients.</p>

<a id="more"></a>
<p><span class="dropcap">T</span>his recipe yields balls of warm, fluffy, buttery mash that you can eat with steaming rice and dal. While there are any number of ways in which you can boil the potatoes, for this recipe, we’ve found that cooking potatoes in an open pot of boiling water will get you the best results. You don’t want the potatoes to absorb too much water while they are cooking, as usually happens in the pressure cooker. In an open pot, you can always stick a fork into the potatoes to check if they are tender. Peeling the potatoes before you add them to the pot is also useful. It eliminates the need to handle hot spuds while removing their skins.</p>
<p>Our favourite way, however, to cook potatoes for this recipe is to put the halved or quartered pieces into the same pot of water as your rice. That way, your <em>alu sheddho</em> is ready at nearly the same time as your rice and there is one less pot to wash at the end of the meal.</p>

<hr>
<p><strong>COOKING TIME</strong> 20 minutes<br><strong>YIELDS</strong> 4 balls of <em>alu sheddho</em></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="Ingredients"><a href="#Ingredients" class="headerlink" title="Ingredients"></a>Ingredients</h2><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:right">Quantity</th>
<th>Ingredient</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">340 g</td>
<td>Potatoes (boiled)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">2 pieces</td>
<td>Green chillies (finely chopped)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">12 g</td>
<td>Ghee or butter or mustard oil (any one)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">4 g</td>
<td>Salt</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="Equipment"><a href="#Equipment" class="headerlink" title="Equipment"></a>Equipment</h2><ul>
<li>Boiling pot</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Appliances"><a href="#Appliances" class="headerlink" title="Appliances"></a>Appliances</h2><ul>
<li>Stove</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Method"><a href="#Method" class="headerlink" title="Method"></a>Method</h2><ol>
<li>Peel the potatoes and cut them in quarters.</li>
<li>Place the pieces in a pot of water and set them to boil.</li>
<li>Cook the potatoes till they are tender. Use a fork or knife to check if they are done.</li>
<li>Drain the water and transfer the boiled potatoes onto a plate or mixing dish.</li>
<li>While they are still hot, mash the potatoes with a fork.</li>
<li>Add the fat of your choice (ghee or butter or mustard oil), green chillies, and salt.</li>
<li>Continue mashing with a fork or by hand till the mixture is smooth and lump-free.</li>
<li>Form into balls and serve.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="Served-with"><a href="#Served-with" class="headerlink" title="Served with"></a>Served with</h2><ul>
<li>Dal</li>
<li>Rice</li>
</ul>
<script type="application/ld+json">
{
  "@context": "http://schema.org/",
  "@type": "Recipe",
  "name": "Alu sheddho",
  "author": "Bong Eats",
  "image": "https://res.cloudinary.com/dmpeew57x/image/upload/v1478835725/thumbs/alu-sheddho_thumbnail_small.jpg",
  "description": "This is the Bengali version of the mashed potato in its most basic form. It is made up of just four ingredients.",
  "prepTime": "PT5M",
  "totalTime": "PT20M",
  "recipeYield": "4",
  "recipeIngredient": [
    "Potatoes    340 g",
    "Green chillies    2 g (or 2 pieces)",
    "Ghee | butter | mustard oil    12 g",
    "Salt    4 g"
  ],
  "recipeInstructions": [
    "1 Peel the potatoes and cut them into pieces 5 cm large.",
    "2 Place them in a pot of water and set them to boil.",
    "3 Cook the potatoes till they are tender. Use a fork or knife to check if they are done.",
    "4 Drain the water and transfer the boiled potatoes onto a plate or mixing dish.",
    "5 While they are still hot, mash the potatoes with a fork.",
    "6 Add the fat of your choice (ghee or butter or mustard oil), green chillies, and salt.",
    "7 Continue mashing with the fork or by hand till the mixture is smooth and lump-free.",
    "8 Form into balls and serve."
   ]
}
</script>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p class=&quot;post-byline&quot;&gt;Boiled potatoes, flavoured with green chillies and a fat of your choice&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;post-intro&quot;&gt;This is the Bengali version of the mashed potato in its most basic form. It is made up of just four simple ingredients.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="recipe" scheme="https://bongeats.com/categories/recipe/"/>
    
    
      <category term="vegetarian" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/vegetarian/"/>
    
      <category term="vegan" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/vegan/"/>
    
      <category term="gluten-free" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/gluten-free/"/>
    
      <category term="boiled" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/boiled/"/>
    
      <category term="dal" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/dal/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Tomato &amp; Curry Pata diye Mosur Dal</title>
    <link href="https://bongeats.com/recipe/tomato-curry-pata-diye-mosur-dal/"/>
    <id>https://bongeats.com/recipe/tomato-curry-pata-diye-mosur-dal/</id>
    <published>2016-07-29T04:39:47.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-11-11T03:48:31.164Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p class="post-byline">A refreshing dal to lighten up any meal</p>

<p class="post-intro">A lentil soup flavoured with mustard seeds and curry leaves, made tangy with the liberal use of tomatoes.</p>

<a id="more"></a>
<p><span class="dropcap">T</span>his dal is sweet and tangy. It incorporates the flavours that result from the timeless combination of mustard seeds and curry leaves crackling in hot oil. This dish is wonderfully cooling—perfect for a summer’s afternoon.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>COOKING TIME</strong> 20 minutes<br><strong>YIELDS</strong> 5 servings</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="Ingredients"><a href="#Ingredients" class="headerlink" title="Ingredients"></a>Ingredients</h2><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:right">Quantity</th>
<th>Ingredient</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">15 g</td>
<td>Mustard oil</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">2 g (or ½ tsp)</td>
<td>Mustard seeds</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">2 pieces</td>
<td>Dried red chillies</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">3 g</td>
<td>Curry leaves</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">250 g</td>
<td>Tomatoes (diced)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">2 g</td>
<td>Turmeric powder</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">15 g</td>
<td>Salt</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">55 g</td>
<td>Sugar</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">100 g</td>
<td>Mosur dal</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">550 g</td>
<td>Water</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="Equipment"><a href="#Equipment" class="headerlink" title="Equipment"></a>Equipment</h2><ul>
<li>Boiling pot | pressure cooker</li>
<li>Beater | balloon whisk | fork | <em>dal’er kaanta</em></li>
<li>Frying pan | saucepan | <em>kadai</em></li>
<li>Ladle | Large spoon</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Appliances"><a href="#Appliances" class="headerlink" title="Appliances"></a>Appliances</h2><ul>
<li>Stove</li>
<li>Pressure cooker (optional)</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Method"><a href="#Method" class="headerlink" title="Method"></a>Method</h2><ol>
<li>Wash the dal thoroughly with plenty of water, making sure to rinse and repeat at least twice.</li>
<li>Place the washed and drained dal in a pressure cooker with 550 g of water. You can also cook the dal over the stove in a lidded pot, but make sure to take 650 g of water instead of 550 g to compensate for evaporation.</li>
<li>Boil till you see the broken grains of dal. If using a pressure cooker, cook on medium-high heat till you hear the first whistle. Turn off the heat and let the pressure release on its own.</li>
<li>Whisk the boiled dal with a beater till you can no longer see the individual grains.</li>
<li>Heat oil in a pan.</li>
<li>Temper it with the dried red chillies, mustard seeds, and half of the curry leaves.</li>
<li>Add the tomatoes, salt, and turmeric, and cook on low heat till the tomatoes are softened.</li>
<li>Add in the whisked dal.</li>
<li>Add the sugar and the remaining curry leaves.</li>
<li>Allow the dal to boil on medium heat for 5–7 minutes.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="Served-with"><a href="#Served-with" class="headerlink" title="Served with"></a>Served with</h2><ul>
<li><em>Bhaja</em> | <em>torkari</em></li>
<li>Rice</li>
</ul>
<script type="application/ld+json">
{
  "@context": "http://schema.org/",
  "@type": "Recipe",
  "name": "Tomato & curry pata diye mosur dal",
  "author": "Bong Eats",
  "image": "https://res.cloudinary.com/dmpeew57x/image/upload/v1478835725/thumbs/tomato-curry-pata-dal_thumbnail_small.jpg",
  "description": "A lentil soup flavoured with mustard seeds and curry leaves, made tangy with the liberal use of tomatoes.",
  "prepTime": "PT10M",
  "totalTime": "PT20M",
  "recipeYield": "5",
  "recipeIngredient": [
    "Mustard oil    15 g",
    "Mustard seeds    2 g (or ½ tsp)",
    "Dried red chillies    2 pcs",
    "Curry leaves    3 g",
    "Tomatoes (diced)    250 g",
    "Turmeric powder    2 g",
    "Salt    15 g",
    "Sugar    55 g",
    "Mosur dal    100 g",
    "Water    550 g"
  ],
  "recipeInstructions": [
    "1 Rinse the dal well and drain the water.",
    "2 Place washed dal in a pressure cooker with 550 g water.",
    "3 Boil till you see the broken grains of dal. If using a pressure cooker, cook on medium-high heat till you hear the first whistle. Turn off the heat and let the pressure release on its own.",
    "4 Whisk the boiled dal till you can no longer see the individual grains.",
    "5 Heat oil in a pan.",
    "6 Temper it with the dried red chillies, mustard seeds, and half of the curry leaves.",
    "7 Add the tomatoes, salt, and turmeric, and cook on low heat till the tomatoes are softened.",
    "8 Add in the whisked dal.",
    "9 Add the sugar and the remaining curry leaves.",
    "10 Allow it to boil on medium heat for 5–7 minutes."
   ]
}
</script>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p class=&quot;post-byline&quot;&gt;A refreshing dal to lighten up any meal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;post-intro&quot;&gt;A lentil soup flavoured with mustard seeds and curry leaves, made tangy with the liberal use of tomatoes.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="recipe" scheme="https://bongeats.com/categories/recipe/"/>
    
    
      <category term="vegetarian" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/vegetarian/"/>
    
      <category term="vegan" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/vegan/"/>
    
      <category term="gluten-free" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/gluten-free/"/>
    
      <category term="dal" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/dal/"/>
    
      <category term="mosur dal" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/mosur-dal/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Luchi</title>
    <link href="https://bongeats.com/recipe/luchi/"/>
    <id>https://bongeats.com/recipe/luchi/</id>
    <published>2016-07-29T04:39:47.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-11-17T06:10:11.284Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p class="post-byline">A light, flaky, puffed-up, deep-fried, sublime bread</p>

<p class="post-intro">We share with you the tips and tricks to making the perfect <em>luchis</em>, including a special hack for beginners.</p>

<a id="more"></a>
<p><span class="dropcap">L</span><em>uchis</em> are made from finely milled flour, as opposed to their close cousins, the <em>puris</em>, which are usually prepared with whole-wheat flour. Our recipe calls for a soft dough, reasonably well-hydrated, that should be kneaded for no less than 5 minutes continuously. With the proportion of the flour to water specified here, the dough may seem tacky at first, but fight the urge to add more flour to counter the wetness. Instead, continue kneading and the water will soon be absorbed into the flour.</p>
<p>Another tip that a lot of beginners would benefit from is this: allow the dough to rest at each stage—after kneading, after portioning, and after shaping the portions into little balls. This relaxes the dough, and makes it easier to handle. Finally, if you have trouble rolling out the <em>luchis</em>, try doing so between two sheets of well-greased baking paper. This helps apply even pressure, which is important if you want the <em>luchis</em> to inflate when fried.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>COOKING TIME</strong> 60 minutes<br><strong>YIELDS</strong> 20 <em>luchis</em></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="Ingredients"><a href="#Ingredients" class="headerlink" title="Ingredients"></a>Ingredients</h2><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:right">Quantity</th>
<th>Ingredient</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">200 g</td>
<td>Flour</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">4 g</td>
<td>Salt</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">10 g</td>
<td>Sugar</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">15 g</td>
<td>Oil</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">110 g</td>
<td>Hot water</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="Equipment"><a href="#Equipment" class="headerlink" title="Equipment"></a>Equipment</h2><ul>
<li>Mixing bowl</li>
<li>Lid for the bowl | plastic wrap</li>
<li>Rolling pin</li>
<li>Frying pan | <em>kadai</em> | wok</li>
<li>Perforated frying spoon | <em>jhanjhri</em></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Appliances"><a href="#Appliances" class="headerlink" title="Appliances"></a>Appliances</h2><ul>
<li>Stove</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Method"><a href="#Method" class="headerlink" title="Method"></a>Method</h2><ol>
<li>Place the flour in a bowl with the salt, sugar, and oil, and distribute the ingredients well by hand.</li>
<li>Add the hot water.</li>
<li>Set your timer for 10 minutes and knead the dough till it is soft and supple. The dough might seem a bit sticky at first, but take your time and knead it well, incorporating all the water.</li>
<li>Cover the dough with either a lid, wet towel, or plastic wrap, and allow it to rest for at least 30 minutes.</li>
<li>Portion the dough in 20 equal balls of 16–17 g each.</li>
<li>Shape each portion of the dough into a round ball. Resting the dough for 5 minutes each before shaping and rolling will make the job easier.</li>
<li>Roll each ball into a disc of about 10 cm in diameter. Beginners may roll out the <em>luchis</em> between two sheets of well-oiled baking paper. This will help apply pressure evenly.</li>
<li>Lower the discs into hot oil set over medium heat and fry the <em>luchis</em> one at a time, gently patting their tops with the flat end of your frying spoon to make them puff.</li>
<li>Drain the fried <em>luchis</em> on a rack, colander, or over paper towels.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="Served-with"><a href="#Served-with" class="headerlink" title="Served with"></a>Served with</h2><ul>
<li>Chhola’r dal</li>
<li>Alu’r torkari</li>
<li>Shada phulkopi’r torkari</li>
<li>Alu’r dom</li>
<li>Dim’er kosha</li>
<li>Kosha maangsho</li>
<li>Payesh</li>
</ul>
<script type="application/ld+json">
{
  "@context": "http://schema.org/",
  "@type": "Recipe",
  "name": "Luchi",
  "author": "Bong Eats",
  "image": "https://res.cloudinary.com/dmpeew57x/image/upload/v1478835725/thumbs/luchi_thumbnail_small.jpg",
  "description": "We share with you the tips and tricks to making the perfect luchis, including a special hack for beginners.",
  "prepTime": "PT30M",
  "totalTime": "PT60M",
  "recipeYield": "20 luchis",
  "recipeIngredient": [
    "Flour 200 g",
    "Salt 4 g",
    "Sugar 10 g",
    "Oil 15 g",
    "Hot water 110 g"
  ],
  "recipeInstructions": [
    "1. Place the flour in a bowl with the salt, sugar, and oil, and distribute the ingredients well by hand.",
    "2. Add the hot water.",
    "3. Set your timer for 10 minutes and knead the dough till it is soft and supple. The dough might seem a bit sticky at first, but take your time and knead it well, incorporating all the water.",
    "4. Cover the dough with either a lid, wet towel, or plastic wrap, and allow it to rest for at least 30 minutes.",
    "5. Portion the dough in 20 equal balls of 16–17g each.",
    "6. Shape each portion of the dough into a round ball. Resting the dough for 5 minutes each before shaping and rolling will make the job easier.",
    "7. Roll each ball into a disc of about 10cm in diameter. Beginners may roll out the luchis between two sheets of well-oiled baking paper. This will help apply pressure evenly.",
    "8. Lower into hot oil set over medium heat and fry the luchis one at a time, gently patting the tops of the luchis with the flat end of your frying spoon to make them puff.",
    "9. Drain the fried luchis on a rack, colander, or over paper towels."
   ]
}
</script>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p class=&quot;post-byline&quot;&gt;A light, flaky, puffed-up, deep-fried, sublime bread&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;post-intro&quot;&gt;We share with you the tips and tricks to making the perfect &lt;em&gt;luchis&lt;/em&gt;, including a special hack for beginners.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="recipe" scheme="https://bongeats.com/categories/recipe/"/>
    
    
      <category term="vegetarian" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/vegetarian/"/>
    
      <category term="vegan" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/vegan/"/>
    
      <category term="snack" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/snack/"/>
    
      <category term="breakfast" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/breakfast/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Narkol&#39;er Bora</title>
    <link href="https://bongeats.com/recipe/narkoler-bora/"/>
    <id>https://bongeats.com/recipe/narkoler-bora/</id>
    <published>2016-07-29T04:39:47.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-11-11T03:46:45.934Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p class="post-byline">Delicately spiced coconut fritters</p>

<p class="post-intro">Q: What’s better than freshly grated coconut?<br>A: Freshly grated coconut, mildly spiced, rolled into balls, and fried till golden brown and delicious.</p>

<a id="more"></a>
<p><span class="dropcap">T</span>hese coconut fritters are a great way to take your <em>bhaat-dal-bhaja</em> game to the next level. They also make for a ridiculously tasty snack.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>COOKING TIME</strong> 20 minutes<br><strong>YIELDS</strong> 9 <em>boras</em></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="Ingredients"><a href="#Ingredients" class="headerlink" title="Ingredients"></a>Ingredients</h2><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:right">Quantity</th>
<th>Ingredient</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">150 g</td>
<td>Coconut (grated)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">10 g</td>
<td>Green chillies (finely chopped)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">15 g</td>
<td>Rice grains (ground to powder)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">6 g</td>
<td>Salt</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">25 g</td>
<td>Sugar</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">30 g</td>
<td>Flour</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">¼ tsp</td>
<td>Kaalo jeere (nigella seeds)</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="Equipment"><a href="#Equipment" class="headerlink" title="Equipment"></a>Equipment</h2><ul>
<li>Mixing bowl</li>
<li>Frying pan | skillet</li>
<li>Perforated frying spoon | <em>jhanjhri</em></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Appliances"><a href="#Appliances" class="headerlink" title="Appliances"></a>Appliances</h2><ul>
<li>Stove</li>
<li>Grater | grinder</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Method"><a href="#Method" class="headerlink" title="Method"></a>Method</h2><ol>
<li>In a dry grinder, finely powder the grains of rice.</li>
<li>Grate the coconut using a grater or an electric grinder.</li>
<li>Chop the green chillies.  </li>
<li>Now, place all the ingredients in a mixing bowl and combine well by hand.</li>
<li>Portion the mixture into balls of 25 g each.</li>
<li>Shape each ball into a disc, making sure the top and bottom are flat for even frying.</li>
<li>Heat oil in a skillet.</li>
<li>Shallow-fry the <em>boras</em> till they are golden brown on both sides.</li>
<li>Remove them from the oil and drain on a rack, colander, or over paper towels.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="Served-with"><a href="#Served-with" class="headerlink" title="Served with"></a>Served with</h2><ul>
<li>Rice</li>
<li>Dal</li>
</ul>
<script type="application/ld+json">
{
  "@context": "http://schema.org/",
  "@type": "Recipe",
  "name": "Narkol'er bora",
  "author": "Bong Eats",
  "image": "https://res.cloudinary.com/dmpeew57x/image/upload/v1478835725/thumbs/narkoler-bora_thumbnail_small.jpg",
  "description": "What's better than freshly grated coconut? Answer: Freshly grated coconut, mildly spiced, rolled into balls, and fried till golden brown and delicious.",
  "prepTime": "PT10M",
  "totalTime": "PT20M",
  "recipeYield": "9 boras",
  "recipeIngredient": [
    "Coconut    150 g",
    "Green chillies    10 g",
    "Rice grains    15 g",
    "Salt    6 g",
    "Sugar    25 g",
    "Flour    30 g",
    "Kaalo jeere (nigella seeds)    1/4 tsp"
  ],
  "recipeInstructions": [
    "1. Place all the ingredients in a mixing bowl and combine well by hand.",
    "2. Portion the mixture into balls of 25g each.",
    "3. Shape each ball into a disc, making sure the top and bottom are flat for even frying.",
    "4. Heat oil in a skillet.",
    "5. Shallow fry the boras till they are golden brown on both sides.",
    "6. Lift them from the oil and drain them on a rack, colander, or over paper towels."
   ]
}
</script>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p class=&quot;post-byline&quot;&gt;Delicately spiced coconut fritters&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;post-intro&quot;&gt;Q: What’s better than freshly grated coconut?&lt;br&gt;A: Freshly grated coconut, mildly spiced, rolled into balls, and fried till golden brown and delicious.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="recipe" scheme="https://bongeats.com/categories/recipe/"/>
    
    
      <category term="vegetarian" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/vegetarian/"/>
    
      <category term="bhaja" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/bhaja/"/>
    
      <category term="fritters" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/fritters/"/>
    
      <category term="snack" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/snack/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Dim&#39;er Dalna</title>
    <link href="https://bongeats.com/recipe/dimer-dalna/"/>
    <id>https://bongeats.com/recipe/dimer-dalna/</id>
    <published>2016-07-29T04:39:47.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-11-11T03:45:33.692Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p class="post-byline">A spicy egg curry</p>

<p class="post-intro">This is one of those rare dishes that manages to be decadent and comforting at the same time</p>

<a id="more"></a>
<p><span class="dropcap">E</span>very part of India has its own iteration of the egg curry. The genius of this version is that it makes use of pan-fried boiled eggs. The boiled eggs, lightly coated in salt and turmeric, are fried in oil till they are golden. The crust makes the gravy adhere to the egg, rather than it just sliding off its smooth surface. This is a hearty, filling curry, best served with a plate of steaming rice.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>COOKING TIME</strong> 40 minutes<br><strong>YIELDS</strong> a serving of 4 eggs</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="Ingredients"><a href="#Ingredients" class="headerlink" title="Ingredients"></a>Ingredients</h2><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:right">Sl</th>
<th style="text-align:right">Quantity</th>
<th>Ingredient</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right"></td>
<td style="text-align:right"><strong>OIL</strong></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">1</td>
<td style="text-align:right">20 g</td>
<td>Mustard oil (for frying)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">2</td>
<td style="text-align:right">20 g</td>
<td>Mustard oil (for cooking)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right"></td>
<td style="text-align:right"><strong><em>PHORON</em> (TEMPERING)</strong></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">3</td>
<td style="text-align:right">2 pieces</td>
<td>Dried red chillies (whole)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">4</td>
<td style="text-align:right">1 piece</td>
<td>Bay leaves (whole)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">5</td>
<td style="text-align:right">2 pieces</td>
<td>Cardamom (whole)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">6</td>
<td style="text-align:right">2 pieces</td>
<td>Cloves (whole)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">7</td>
<td style="text-align:right">1 piece</td>
<td>Cinnamon (whole)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">8</td>
<td style="text-align:right">1 g (or ¼ tsp)</td>
<td>Cumin seeds</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right"></td>
<td style="text-align:right"><strong>EGGS AND VEGETABLES</strong></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">9</td>
<td style="text-align:right">4 pieces</td>
<td>Duck or chicken eggs (boiled)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">10</td>
<td style="text-align:right">4 pieces</td>
<td>Potatoes (diced; 5 cm cubes)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">11</td>
<td style="text-align:right">100 g</td>
<td>Onions (thinly sliced)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">12</td>
<td style="text-align:right">25 g</td>
<td>Tomatoes (diced)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">13</td>
<td style="text-align:right">15 g</td>
<td>Ginger paste</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">14</td>
<td style="text-align:right">2 g</td>
<td>Garlic paste</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right"></td>
<td style="text-align:right"><strong>SPICES AND SEASONING</strong></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">15</td>
<td style="text-align:right">2 g</td>
<td>Cumin powder</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">16</td>
<td style="text-align:right">2 g</td>
<td>Coriander powder</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">17</td>
<td style="text-align:right">4 g</td>
<td>Turmeric powder (for the curry)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">18</td>
<td style="text-align:right">¼ tsp</td>
<td>Turmeric powder (for coating the eggs with)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">19</td>
<td style="text-align:right">1 g</td>
<td>Red chilli powder</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">20</td>
<td style="text-align:right">6 g</td>
<td>Salt (for the curry)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">21</td>
<td style="text-align:right">6 g</td>
<td>Salt (for boiling potatoes)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">22</td>
<td style="text-align:right">¼ tsp</td>
<td>Salt (for coating the eggs with)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">23</td>
<td style="text-align:right">15 g</td>
<td>Sugar</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">24</td>
<td style="text-align:right">1 piece</td>
<td>Green chilli (slit)</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="Equipment"><a href="#Equipment" class="headerlink" title="Equipment"></a>Equipment</h2><ul>
<li>Saucepan | boiling pot</li>
<li><em>Kadai</em> | wok | frying pan | cooking pot</li>
<li>Lid for cooking vessel</li>
<li><em>Khunti</em> | long spatula</li>
<li>Microwavable bowl (optional)</li>
<li>Plastic wrap (optional)</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Appliances"><a href="#Appliances" class="headerlink" title="Appliances"></a>Appliances</h2><ul>
<li>Stove</li>
<li>Microwave (optional)</li>
<li>Electric kettle (optional)</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Method"><a href="#Method" class="headerlink" title="Method"></a>Method</h2><p><strong>PART I—BOILING AND FRYING THE EGGS</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Bring a pot of water to a boil.</li>
<li>Lower the eggs (which should be at room temperature; eggs from the refrigerator might crack when added to boiling water) in the water and cook them on low heat for 6 minutes (duck eggs) or 5 minutes (chicken eggs), with the lid on.</li>
<li>Turn off the heat and let the eggs sit in the hot water for another 3 minutes. We want the yolks gooey.</li>
<li>Drain the water and remove the shells.</li>
<li>Prick the eggs all around with a toothpick. This will prevent the eggs from bursting when fried and also allow the gravy to seep to the yolk.</li>
<li>Coat the eggs in ¼ tsp each of salt and turmeric powder.</li>
<li>Fry the eggs in 10 g mustard oil on medium heat for 5 minutes, till they develop an even amber-coloured crust.</li>
<li><p>Set aside.</p>
<p><strong>PART II—BOILING THE POTATOES</strong></p>
</li>
<li>Peel and cut the potatoes in chunks of 5 cm. We need as many pieces of potatoes as there are eggs (four, in this case).</li>
<li>Place them in a microwaveable bowl with 6 g of salt and 2 tablespoons of water.</li>
<li>Cover with cling film and microwave for 3 minutes. Alternatively, you can also boil them on the stove till partially cooked.</li>
<li><p>Set aside.</p>
<p><strong>PART III—PREPARING THE CURRY</strong></p>
</li>
<li>Now, heat 20 g mustard oil in a pan.</li>
<li>Temper the oil with the <em>phoron</em> (dried red chillies, bay leaves, cardamom, cinnamon, cloves, and cumin seeds).</li>
<li>Once the whole spices start to crackle in oil, add the chopped onions and sugar to the pan and fry on medium heat for 5–7 minutes.</li>
<li>Add the ginger paste and minced garlic to the pan, and fry for another 3–4 minutes.</li>
<li>Make a spice paste by adding 50 g water to the cumin powder, coriander powder, turmeric powder, red chilli powder, and salt.</li>
<li>Add this mixture to the pan and cook on medium heat till the water dries off.</li>
<li>Then, add another 50g of water, along with the tomatoes and green chilli, and cook till the water dries off again.</li>
<li>Add the parboiled potatoes and cook on low heat for 2 minutes.</li>
<li>Then add the eggs. Cook for another minute. Stop here if you want <em>dim’er kosha</em>, a rich gravy to accompany your fried rice or <em>luchi</em>. For a lighter curry to eat with steamed rice, proceed to the next step.</li>
<li>Now, add 225 g hot water to the pan. This will form the curry.</li>
<li>Boil for 5–7 minutes with the lid on before removing from the heat.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="Served-with"><a href="#Served-with" class="headerlink" title="Served with"></a>Served with</h2><ul>
<li>Steamed rice</li>
<li>Fried rice</li>
<li>Luchi</li>
</ul>
<script type="application/ld+json">
{
  "@context": "http://schema.org/",
  "@type": "Recipe",
  "name": "Dim'er dalna",
  "author": "Bong Eats",
  "image": "https://res.cloudinary.com/dmpeew57x/image/upload/v1478835725/thumbs/dimer-dalna_thumbnail._smalljpg.jpg",
  "description": "This is a hearty, filling curry. It is the perfect accompaniment to a plate of steaming rice.",
  "prepTime": "PT10M",
  "totalTime": "PT30M",
  "recipeYield": "4 eggs",
  "recipeIngredient": [
    "Mustard oil (for frying) 20 g",
    "Mustard oil (for cooking) 20 g",
    "Dried red chillies 2 pieces",
    "Bay leaves 1 piece",
    "Cardamom    2    pieces",
    "Cloves    2    pieces",
    "Cinnamon    1 piece",
    "Cumin seeds 1 g (or ¼ tsp)",
    "Eggs    4    pieces",
    "Potatoes    4    pieces",
    "Onions    115    g",
    "Tomatoes    25 g",
    "Ginger paste    15 g",
    "Garlic    2    g",
    "Cumin powder    2    g",
    "Coriander powder 2    g",        
    "Turmeric powder 4 g    (plus ¼ tsp extra for frying the eggs)",
    "Red chilli powder 1 g",
    "Salt (for the curry)    6    g",
    "Salt (for boiling potatoes) 6 g",
    "Sugar 15 g",
    "Green chillies    1    g (or 1 piece)"
  ],
  "recipeInstructions": [
    "1 Bring a pot of water to a boil.",
    "2 Lower the eggs (which should be at room temperature; eggs from the refrigerator might crack when added to boiling water) in the water and cook them on low heat for 6 minutes (duck eggs) or 5 minutes (chicken eggs), with the lid on.",
    "3 Turn off the heat and let the eggs sit in the hot water for another 3 minutes. We want the yolks gooey.",
    "4 Drain the water and remove the shells.",
    "5 Prick the eggs all around with a toothpick. This will prevent the eggs from bursting when fried and allow the gravy to seep into the yoke.",
    "6 Coat the eggs in ¼ tsp each of salt and turmeric powder.",
    "7 Fry the eggs in 10 g mustard oil on medium heat for 5 minutes, till they develop an even amber-coloured crust.",
    "8 Set aside.",
    "9 Peel and cut the potatoes in chunks of 5 cm. We need as many pieces of potatoes as there are eggs (four, in this case).",
    "10 Place them in a microwaveable bowl.",
    "11 Add 6 g of salt and 2 tablespoons of water.",
    "12 Cover with cling film and microwave for 3 minutes. Alternatively, you can also boil them on the stove till partially cooked.",
    "13 Set aside.",
    "14 Now, heat 20 g mustard oil in a pan.",
    "15 Temper the oil with the phoron.",
    "16 Add the chopped onions and sugar to the pan and fry on medium heat for 5–7 minutes.",
    "17 Add the ginger paste and minced garlic to the pan, and fry for another 3–4 minutes.",
    "18 Make a spice paste by adding 50 g water to the cumin powder, coriander powder, turmeric powder, red chilli powder, and salt.",
    "19 Add this mixture to the pan and cook on medium heat till the water dries off.",
    "20 Then, add another 50g of water, along with the tomatoes and green chilli, and cook till the water dries off.",
    "21 Add the parboiled potatoes and cook on low heat for 2 minutes.",
    "22 Then add the eggs. Cook for another minute. Stop here if you want dim’er kosha, a rich gravy to accompany your fried rice or luchi. For a lighter curry to eat with steamed rice, proceed to the next step.",
    "23 Now, add 225 g hot water to the pan. This will form the curry.",
    "24 Boil for 5 minutes with lid on before removing from the heat."
   ]
}
</script>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p class=&quot;post-byline&quot;&gt;A spicy egg curry&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;post-intro&quot;&gt;This is one of those rare dishes that manages to be decadent and comforting at the same time&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="recipe" scheme="https://bongeats.com/categories/recipe/"/>
    
    
      <category term="gluten-free" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/gluten-free/"/>
    
      <category term="non-vegetarian" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/non-vegetarian/"/>
    
      <category term="dalna" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/dalna/"/>
    
      <category term="curry" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/curry/"/>
    
      <category term="egg" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/egg/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Sooji</title>
    <link href="https://bongeats.com/recipe/sooji/"/>
    <id>https://bongeats.com/recipe/sooji/</id>
    <published>2016-07-29T04:39:47.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-11-11T03:47:56.688Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p class="post-byline">A sweet semolina porridge</p>

<p class="post-intro">Semolina is the broken endosperm of wheat, waiting to be ground into flour. But before it gets there, we use it to make a delightful porridge.</p>

<a id="more"></a>
<p><span class="dropcap">T</span>his version of the <em>sooji</em> is creamy, non-greasy, and lightly spiced with cardamom. It is subtle and sweet, but not so sweet that you cannot eat it as breakfast cereal first thing in the morning.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>COOKING TIME</strong> 10 minutes<br><strong>YIELDS</strong> 2 servings</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="Ingredients"><a href="#Ingredients" class="headerlink" title="Ingredients"></a>Ingredients</h2><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:right">Quantity</th>
<th>Ingredient</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">75 g</td>
<td>Semolina or sooji</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">1 piece</td>
<td>Bay leaf</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">2 pieces</td>
<td>Cardamom</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">10 g</td>
<td>Ghee</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">20 g</td>
<td>Cashew nuts (split)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">20 g</td>
<td>Raisins</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">500 g</td>
<td>Milk</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">40 g</td>
<td>Sugar</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:right">a pinch</td>
<td>Salt</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="Equipment"><a href="#Equipment" class="headerlink" title="Equipment"></a>Equipment</h2><ul>
<li><em>Kadai</em> | wok | frying pan | cooking pot</li>
<li><em>Khunti</em> | long spatula</li>
<li>Balloon whisk (optional)</li>
<li>Microwavable bowl (optional)</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Appliances"><a href="#Appliances" class="headerlink" title="Appliances"></a>Appliances</h2><ul>
<li>Stove</li>
<li>Microwave (optional)</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Method"><a href="#Method" class="headerlink" title="Method"></a>Method</h2><ol>
<li>Heat the milk till it’s lukewarm (either in the microwave or on the stove).</li>
<li>Crush the cardamom pods roughly to release flavour.</li>
<li>Split the cashew nuts in half, lengthwise.</li>
<li>Heat ghee in a pan set on low heat.</li>
<li>Fry the split cashew nuts till golden brown.</li>
<li>Add the bay leaf and crushed cardamom pods.</li>
<li>Add in the semolina.</li>
<li>Roast on low heat for 4–5 minutes, stirring continuously for even cooking.</li>
<li>When the semolina starts to take on a slight amber colour and gives out a nutty smell, add the warm milk, all at one go.</li>
<li>Whisk vigorously for about 30 seconds to ensure that no lumps remain.</li>
<li>Add the raisins, sugar, and a pinch of salt.</li>
<li>Cook for 2–3 minutes till the sooji thickens. Stir frequently to avoid the formation of a crust on the surface. The longer you keep the porridge in contact with heat, the more it will thicken. If you prefer a runnier porridge, remove from the pan immediately. If you like it more well-set, turn off the heat and let it sit in the pan for another minute or so.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="Served-with"><a href="#Served-with" class="headerlink" title="Served with"></a>Served with</h2><ul>
<li>Tea</li>
</ul>
<script type="application/ld+json">
{
  "@context": "http://schema.org/",
  "@type": "Recipe",
  "name": "Sooji",
  "author": "Bong Eats",
  "image": "https://res.cloudinary.com/dmpeew57x/image/upload/v1478835725/thumbs/sooji_thumbnail_small.jpg",
  "description": "Semolina is the broken endosperm of wheat, waiting to be ground into flour. But before it gets there, we use it to make a delightful porridge.",
  "prepTime": "PT2M",
  "totalTime": "PT10M",
  "recipeYield": "2",
  "recipeIngredient": [
    "Semolina (sooji)    75 g",
    "Bay leaf    1 piece",
    "Cardamom    2 pieces",
    "Ghee    10 g",
    "Cashew nuts 20 g",
    "Raisins    20 g",
    "Milk    500 g",
    "Sugar    40 g",
    "Salt    a pinch"
  ],
  "recipeInstructions": [
    "1. Heat milk till it’s lukewarm (either in the microwave on the stove).",
    "2. Crush the cardamom pods roughly to release flavour.",
    "3. Split the cashew nuts in half, lengthwise.",
    "4. Heat ghee in a pan set on low heat.",
    "5. Fry the split cashew nuts till golden brown.",
    "6. Add the bay leaf and crushed cardamom pods.",
    "7. Add the semolina.",
    "8. Roast on low heat for 4–5 minutes, stirring continuously for even cooking.",
    "9. When the semolina starts to take on a slight colour and gives out a nutty smell, add the warm milk, all at one go. This is done to avoid the chances of the semolina clumping from the sudden addition of  the liquid.",
    "10. Whisk vigorously for about 30 seconds to ensure that no lumps remain.",
    "11. Add the raisins, sugar, and a pinch of salt.",
    "12. Cook for 2–3 minutes till the sooji thickens. Stir frequently to avoid the formation of a crust on the surface. The longer you keep the porridge in contact with heat, the more it will thicken. If you prefer a runnier porridge, remove from the pan immediately. If you like it more well-set, turn off the heat and let it sit in the pan for another minute or so."
   ]
}
</script>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p class=&quot;post-byline&quot;&gt;A sweet semolina porridge&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;post-intro&quot;&gt;Semolina is the broken endosperm of wheat, waiting to be ground into flour. But before it gets there, we use it to make a delightful porridge.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="recipe" scheme="https://bongeats.com/categories/recipe/"/>
    
    
      <category term="vegetarian" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/vegetarian/"/>
    
      <category term="snack" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/snack/"/>
    
      <category term="breakfast" scheme="https://bongeats.com/tags/breakfast/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
